[温柔的管弦乐演奏]
[GENTLE ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING]
大卫. 马兰: 好的，这是 CS50的介绍
DAVID MALAN: All right, this is CS50's Introduction
用 Python 编程。
to Programming with Python.
我的名字是大卫马兰，这是我们关于函数和变量的一周。
My name is David Malan and this is our week on functions and variables.
但很可能你们中的大多数，从来没有真正编程过。
But odds are, many of you, most of you, have never actually programmed before.
让我们从这个开始。
So let's start by doing just that.
让我打开我的电脑
Let me go ahead here and open up my computer
上面有一个叫做 Visual Studio Code 或者 VS 的程序
and on it, a program called Visual Studio Code or VS
代码，这只是一个非常流行的程序现在
Code, which is just a very popular program nowadays
实际编写代码。
for actually writing code.
现在，您不必使用这个特定的工具编写代码。
Now, you don't have to write code using this particular tool.
事实上，在一天结束的时候，我们所需要的
In fact, all we need at the end of the day
是一个所谓的文本编辑器，一个编写文本的程序。
is a so-called text editor, a program for writing text.
而且，如果你真的想要，你甚至可以用一些东西
And, heck, if you really want, you could even use something
比如谷歌文档或微软 Word。
like Google Docs or Microsoft Word.
你得用正确的格式保存,
You'd have to save it in the right format,
但实际上，到最后，你所需要的只是一个写文本的程序
but really, at the end of the day, all you need is a program for writing text
因为代码就是短信。
because that's what code is-- text.
现在在这个特殊的程序中，我要去
Now within this particular program, I'm going
能够创建一个或多个文件
to have the ability to create one or more files
通过屏幕的顶部。
via this top portion of the screen.
我会直接跳进去
And I'm going to do so by diving right in
然后在屏幕底部做这个动作。
and doing this at the bottom of my screen.
在我的屏幕底部有一个所谓的终端窗口
At the bottom of my screen is a so-called terminal window
这是一个命令行接口或 CLI 接口
and this is a command line interface or CLI interface to the underlying
计算机，无论是你的 Mac 或 PC，甚至是云中的某个服务器。
computer, be it your Mac or your PC or even some server in the cloud.
我现在要写的就是“代码”然后
And what I'm going to do here is literally write, "code" and then
我想要编码的文件的名称，例如 Hello.py。
the name of the file that I want to code, for instance, Hello.py.
我们很快就会看到，用 Python 编写的任何程序通常都有一个文件
As we'll soon see, any program that you write in Python generally has a file
以. py 结尾的名称，向计算机表明它确实是一个程序
name that ends in .py to indicate to the computer that it's indeed a program
用 Python 写的。
written in Python.
现在你可以看到在我的屏幕顶部，我有一个闪烁的光标,
Now you'll see here at the top of my screen, I have a blinking cursor,
第一行，也就是我代码的第一行要去的地方
a line one-- which is where the very first line of my code is going to go--
然后只有一个标签，提醒我这个文件的名称 Hello.py。
and then just a tab that reminds me of the name of this file Hello.py.
我对巨蟒一无所知
And without even knowing much Python, I'm
我将在这里写我的第一个程序，如下所示
going to write my very first program here as follows--
Print (“ hello，world”)。
print("hello,world").
你会在我的键盘上看到我的一些想法
And you'll see that, at my keyboard, some of my thoughts
对我来说已经结束了。
were finished for me.
我只要输入一个括号另一个就会自动出现,
I only had to type one parenthesis and the other one automatically appeared,
这就是我们将要看到的工具的特性，比如这个工具。
and that's just the feature that we'll see of tools like this tool here.
即使你以前没有编过程序,
Now even if you've never programmed before,
你可以猜测，推断这个简单的程序将要做什么。
odds are you can guess, infer what this simple program is going to do.
而且只有一行。 print (“ hello，world”)。
And it's only one line. print("hello,world").
事实上，当我最终运行这个程序时,
Indeed, when I run this program ultimately,
它只会说，你好，世界。
it's just going to say, Hello to the world.
事实上，这是一个非常著名的
And, in fact, this is a very famous--
也许是最正统的... 程序
perhaps the most canonical-- program that you
可以用 Python 或任何其他语言编写第一个程序,
can write as your very first program in Python or any other language,
这就是我在这里所做的。
and so that's what I've done here.
但是在我的 Mac，PC，甚至我的手机上，我通常都有这个习惯,
But on my Mac, my PC, even my phone, I'm generally in the habit,
像你一样，通过双击图标来运行程序
like you, of running programs by double clicking an icon
或者只是点击屏幕。
or just tapping on the screen.
但我在这里没有看到这样的图标。
But I see no such icons here.
事实上，这是因为我的界面，至少我现在的 Mac
And in fact, that's because my interface to at least my current Mac
或者 PC 或者云中的某个服务器，也只是一个 CLI ——
or PC or some server in the cloud, is again only a CLI--
命令行界面-即使它
command line interface-- which even though it
可能会觉得这是从菜单、按钮和图标退后了一步
might feel like it's a step back from the menus and buttons and icons
我们每天都认为理所当然你会发现，我们认为,
that you and I take for granted every day, you'll find, we think,
它最终是一个更加强大的界面
that it's ultimately a much more powerful interface and incredibly
在现实世界中很受程序员的欢迎。
popular to use among programmers in the real world.
要运行这个程序，我必须使用一个命令
So to run this program, I'm going to have to use a command
我要把光标移回屏幕底部
and I'm going to move my cursor back down to the bottom of the screen
在这里我已经运行了一个命令——
here where previously I already ran one command--
命令代码，它具有在我的计算机中打开 VS 代码的效果,
the command Code which has the effect of opening VS Code in my computer,
然后我把我想要编码的文件的名字传过去。
and then I passed in the name of the file that I wanted to code up.
现在我有机会输入第二条命令,
Now I have a chance to type a second command,
你会看到第二个美元符号。
and you'll see I see a second dollar sign.
这里的美元符号并不代表任何货币,
Now the dollar sign here doesn't indicate any kind of currency or money,
它只是通常使用的符号
it just is the symbol that's generally used
来指示提示符——命令行接口所需的位置
to indicate your prompt-- where the command line interface wants
你来下达命令。
you to put those commands.
现在我可以运行的命令是这样的——
Now the command I can run here is going to be this--
我要运行 Python of Hello.py。
I'm going to run Python of Hello.py.
为什么？
Now why is that?
事实证明，当我用 Python 这样的语言编写代码时,
Well, it turns out that when I actually write code in a language like Python,
当然存在那个文件里
it's of course stored in that file--
Py，但我需要从头到尾解释代码,
Hello.py, but I need to interpret the code top to bottom,
从左到右，以便计算机知道该做什么。
left to right so that the computer knows what to do.
事实上，在一天结束的时候，即使你真的不知道
Indeed, at the end of the day, even if you don't really
你可能对电脑很了解
know much about computers, you've probably
听说计算机只能理解零和一，所谓的二进制
heard the computers only understand zeros and ones, the so-called binary
系统。
system.
如果是这样的话，那就写上“打印”和括号
Well if that's the case, then something that says "print" and parentheses
引用“你好世界”，不一定是0和1。
and quote unquote hello world, is not surely zeros and ones.
我们得想办法把它翻译成0和1
We have to somehow translate it into the zeros and ones
计算机能够理解的。
that the computer understands.
幸运的是，只要你提前安装了这样的程序,
Now fortunately, so long as you've installed such a program in advance,
除了 Python 语言，还有一个程序。
there's a program as well as a language called Python.
所以 Python 不仅仅是一种我们用来编写代码的语言,
So Python is not only a language in which we're going to write code,
它也是一个程序，也被称为解释器
it's also a program otherwise known as an interpreter
你可以在自己的 Mac 或 PC 或者云服务器上免费安装
that you install for free on your own Mac or PC or some server in the cloud
然后你可以运行这个程序，这个解释器，作为输入传递给它
and you can then run that program, that interpreter, passing to it as input
你的文件名就像我的一样 Hello.py。
the name of your file like mine here, Hello.py.
然后那个程序，那个解释器
And then that program, that interpreter, will
处理从上到下，从左到右的阅读过程
handle the process of reading it top to bottom, left to right
然后有效地转换成那些0和1
and translating it effectively into those zeros and ones
计算机能够理解的。
that the computer can understand.
那我们就这么做吧。
So let's do just that.
让我们回到 VS 代码。
Let me go back to VS Code here.
我已经输入了 Python of Hello.py，但是没有按回车键。
I already typed out Python of Hello.py but I didn't get hit Enter.
这就是现在开始执行这个命令的原因
And that's what's now going to kick off this command
希望如果我没有搞砸这一切,
and hopefully, if I didn't mess any of this up,
我应该能看到我的第一个程序在屏幕上的输出。
I should see my very first program's output to the screen.
瞧，你好，世界。
And voila, hello, world.
所以如果你也输入了完全相同的代码
So if you too have typed exactly that same code
并执行完全相同的命令,
and have executed exactly that same command,
在这个例子中，您已经用 Python 编写了第一个程序。
you will have written your very first program in this case in Python.
现在让我们退一步想想,
Well now let's take a step back and consider,
我们到底做了什么
what is it that we actually just did and what
我们在屏幕上看到的是这个吗？
is it we're looking here on the screen?
首先，在大多数编程语言中,
Well first and foremost, in most any programming language,
你可以访问所谓的函数。
you tend to have access to what are called functions.
一个函数就像一个动作或动词
A function is like an action or a verb that
让你在程序中做一些事情。
lets you do something in the program.
一般来说，任何语言都有一些预设的集合
And generally speaking, any language comes with some predetermined set
一些非常基本的动作或动词
of functions-- some very basic actions or verbs that the computer will already
知道如何为你做，语言，真的,
know how to do for you, that the language, really,
会知道如何为你做。
will know how to do for you.
而你，程序员，人类，可以随意使用这些函数
And you, the programmer, the human, can use those functions at will
让电脑来做这些事情。
to get the computer to do those things.
现在这里讨论的程序 Hello.py 正在使用一个函数。
Now the program in question here, Hello.py is using one function.
你也许能猜到是什么。
And you could perhaps guess what it is.
当然，这个函数就是这个函数 print
That function is, of course, going to be this function print
而打印功能，当然，没有
and that print function, of course, doesn't
打印一些预定的文本字符串。
print some preordained string of text.
也就是说，你想打印什么它就打印什么。
That is to say, it prints whatever it is you want it to print.
在这里，我们是否还有另一个术语
And here too, do we have another piece of terminology in the world
指编程，即参数。
of programming, namely arguments.
参数是函数的输入，它会以某种方式影响函数的行为。
An argument is an input to a function that somehow influences its behavior.
当然，发明巨蟒的人,
The people who invented Python, of course,
不一定知道你和我是什么关系
didn't necessarily know what it is you and I
想要打印到屏幕上，所以他们设计了这个打印
are going to want to print to the screen, so they designed this print
函数使用这些括号的能力
function using these parentheses with the ability
输入一些文本字符串
to take as input some string of text, be it
在英语或任何其他人类语言，这是
in English or any other human language, that is
你希望这个函数最终打印到屏幕上的内容。
what you want this function ultimately to print onto the screen.
那么这个程序最终在屏幕上做什么呢？
And what is it that the program is ultimately doing on the screen?
当然是印刷了。
Well, it's printing, of course.
它在向我们问好，屏幕上的世界。
It's showing us hello, world on the screen.
这通常在编程中被称为副作用。
And that's generally in programming known as a side effect.
它可以是视觉的，也可以是音频的。
It can be visual, it can be audio.
在这种情况下，它是出现在屏幕上的东西
In this case, it's something that appears on the screen
和功能，因此，确实可以有这些副作用。
and functions, therefore, can indeed have these side effects.
作为动词或动作，他们可以做的事情之一是
One of the things they can do as this verb or action is
显示在屏幕上作为副作用，类似这些话
to display on the screen as a side effect, something like those words
我们想..
that we wanted--
你好，世界。
hello, world.
这是我的第一个项目，我感觉很好。
So that's my first program and, you know, I'm feeling pretty good.
一切都按计划进行。
Everything worked as planned.
我没有犯任何错误，但是，说实话,
I didn't make any mistakes, but, honestly,
当你学习如何编程，甚至
when you're learning how to program and even
一旦你多年后学会了如何编程，你就会犯错误。
once you've learned how to program years later, you're going to make mistakes.
当然，这些错误都是提到的
And those mistakes, of course, are referred
一个你可能已经知道的术语，那就是 bug。
to a term you might already know, which is that of a bug.
Bug 是程序中的一个错误，它们可以有很多种形式。
A bug is a mistake in a program and they can take so many forms.
也许你会感到欣慰，因为你知道在接下来的几周里,
And take comfort, perhaps, in knowing that over the coming weeks,
你会犯很多错误。
you're going to make so many mistakes.
你的代码会有很多错误，就像我一样
You're going to have so many bugs in your code, just like I did
就像现在一样。
and just as I still do.
那些虫子本身就是错误
And those bugs themselves are just mistakes
都是你要解决的问题。
that are problems for you to solve.
在接下来的几周里，我们会给你
And over the weeks to come, we're going to give you
有很多脑力和技术工具可以帮助你解决这些问题。
a lot of tools both mental and technical via which you can solve those problems.
但是，如果在第一次编写程序时遇到这种情况，请不要气馁
But just don't get discouraged if when writing your program for the first time
甚至第一次都不管用，随着时间的推移，随着练习,
it doesn't even work that first time, it will with time, with practice,
而且经验丰富。
and with experience.
现在让我故意犯一个错误
So let me deliberately now make a mistake
有一个非零的机会，我可能已经意外地做了,
that there was a non-zero chance I might have done accidentally already,
但我很幸运。
but I got lucky.
让我继续，假设我忘了
Let me go ahead and just suppose I forgot
包括括括号之类的东西
to include something like the closing parenthesis
在这行代码的末尾。
at the end of this line of code.
代码几乎是正确的，差不多99% 都是正确的,
The code is almost correct, it's like 99% of the way there,
但现在我已经指出来了，这很明显
but now that I've pointed it out, it's pretty obvious
少了一个括号。
that it's missing that closed parenthesis.
但即使是那些看似微不足道的小细节，你和我作为人类
But even little, seemingly minor details like that, that you and I as humans
也不会在乎。
wouldn't really care about.
如果你正在发送电子邮件或短信，无论如何，这只是一个打印错误。
And if you're sending an email or a text message, whatever, it's just a typo.
没什么大不了的。
It's not that big a deal.
这对电脑来说将是一件大事。
It is going to be a big deal to the computer.
一台电脑会直接把你带到,
A computer is going to take you literally,
如果你没有以语言所期望的方式完成你的思想,
and if you don't finish your thought in the way the language expects,
它根本就不会运行。
it's not going to necessarily run at all.
我们开始吧。
So let's do this.
我现在要清空底部的屏幕
I'm going to go ahead here and clear my screen down at the bottom
这样我就可以重新开始，我要继续跑了
just so I can start fresh, and I'm going to go ahead and run
我的程序的这个版本后，已经作出了更改，删除
this version of my program after having made that change by deleting
括号。
the parenthesis.
我将继续输入 Python，这次是 Hello.py
I'm going to go ahead and type Python again of Hello.py and this time
当我点击回车，我希望我能看到你好，世界,
when I hit Enter, I'm hoping I'm going to see hello, world,
但是这里我们在屏幕上有一个错误，一个所谓的语法
but here we have an error on the screen, a so-called syntax
错误，指的是我在键盘上犯了一个错误。
error, which refers to my having made a mistake at my keyboard.
幸运的是，这个很简单。
And this one, fortunately, is pretty straightforward.
它确实说明了这个开括号从来没有关闭过。
It indeed says that this open parenthesis was never closed.
所以这可能是相当直观的。
And so that's probably pretty intuitive.
现在我需要做的，当然是关闭它。
Now what I need to do, I need to, of course, to close it.
不幸的是，有时我们将在未来几周看到的错误消息
Unfortunately, sometimes the error messages we'll see in the coming weeks
就不会那么方便用户了。
are not going to be nearly that user-friendly.
但是，再一次，用经验，用实践，你会
But there too again, with experience, with practice, will you
更好地调试这些程序。
get better at debugging such programs.
现在让我确认一下我确实正确地修复了它。
Let me now make sure that I indeed fixed it correctly.
现在让我继续运行 Hello.py 并点击 Enter，瞧,
Let me go ahead and run now Hello.py and hit Enter and, voila,
我们又有生意了。
we're back in business.
让我在这里暂停一下，看看我们现在是否有任何问题
Well let me pause here and see if we have any questions now
关于 Python 本身，编写或运行这些程序中最简单的一个。
about Python itself, writing, or running even the simplest of these programs.
观众: 我可以在一个单词中写代码吗? 或者，比如，微软的 Excel？
AUDIENCE: Could I write code inside a word or, for example, Microsoft Excel?
这样做的障碍是什么？
And what's the barrier to doing that?
大卫 · 马兰: 一个非常好的问题，允许
DAVID MALAN: A really good question, and allow
我非常明确地对整个互联网说
me to very explicitly say to the entire internet
您不应该使用 MicrosoftWord 编写代码。
that you should not write code with Microsoft Word.
我提到这个只是因为它是一个工具
I mentioned that only because it's a tool via which
你可以写文本，代码，在一天结束的时候，只是文本。
you can write text and code is, at the end of the day, just text.
但这不是做这项工作的合适工具。
But it's not the right tool for the job.
我们不需要大胆的面对，下划线，段落等等。
We don't need bold facing, underlining, paragraphs and the like.
我们通常想要一些比微软 Word 或谷歌文档简单得多的东西。
We generally want something much simpler than Microsoft Word or Google Docs.
因此 VS Code 只是一个更通用的文本编辑器的例子。
And so VS Code is an example of just a more general purpose text editor.
它在生活中的目的是允许你，人类，编辑文本。
Its purpose in life is to allow you, the human, to edit text.
如今，这些文本编辑器具有更多的特性。
Nowadays these text editors come with many more features.
事实上，你会注意到即使在我的代码中,
In fact, you'll notice that even in my code here,
虽然只是一行字，但还是有点色彩的。
even though it's just one line, there's a bit of color to it.
“印刷”这个词对我来说是蓝色的。
The word "print" for me is appearing in blue.
括号是黑色的。
The parentheses are black.
我们会看到，当我们编写更多的代码行，越来越多的行
And we'll see as we write more lines of code, more and more of the lines
将以各种颜色复活。
will come to life in various colors.
这只是文本编辑器的一个特性。
Now that's just one feature of a text editor.
我们还将看到它具有类似这个内置终端窗口的特性。
We'll see too that it has features like this built-in terminal window.
它将拥有一个用于调试或查找问题的内置工具
It's going to have a built-in tool for debugging or finding problems
用密码。
with code.
现在它是一种非常流行的工具,
And it's just a very popular tool nowadays,
但外面还有很多很多其他人。
but there are many, many others out there.
你可以在这门课和以后的课上使用它们。
You're welcome to use them for this course and beyond.
我们只是碰巧在很大程度上用到了这个
We just happen to use this one in large part
因为现在你也可以在云端免费使用 VS 代码。
too because you can also use VS Code nowadays for free in the cloud.
这里还有一个关于 Python 编程的问题怎么样
How about one other question here on programming with Python
还是 hello，world 或者更一般的语法？
or hello, world or syntax more generally?
观众: 是的，我想问如果它不是
AUDIENCE: Yeah I was trying to ask if it's not
可以使用终端窗口运行计算机吗？
possible to run the computer using the terminal window?
大卫. 马兰: 我想我听到的是不是——
DAVID MALAN: I think I heard is it not--
是否有可能在没有终端窗口的情况下运行程序？
if it's possible to run the program without the terminal window?
你.
Are you--
观众: 是的，先生。
AUDIENCE: Yes, sir.
大卫 · 马兰: 好吧，你又为我愣住了。
DAVID MALAN: OK, you froze for me again.
但让我来推断一下问题是什么。
But let me infer what the question is.
所以在这个环境中，当我配置我的电脑时,
So in this environment, as I've configured my computer,
我只能通过终端窗口运行这些 Python 程序。
I can only run these Python programs via the terminal window.
这对我，程序员，或者那些
Now that's good for me, the programmer, or the person who's
试图学习如何编程，但不是很好
trying to learn how to program, but it's not very good
如果您想发布这个软件，并让其他人使用您的实际代码。
if you want to ship this software and have other people use your actual code.
你完全可以编写程序，然后让其他人使用,
You can absolutely write programs and then allow other people to use,
不是一个命令行界面，而是一个图形用户界面或图形用户界面——
not a command line interface, but a graphical user interface or GUI--
G-U-I，这只是一个机制，也许，我认为,
G-U-I. This is just one mechanism and perhaps, I think,
开始编写代码的最佳方法
the best one with which to start writing code
因为最终它会给我们更多的控制权。
because eventually it's going to give us a lot more control.
请允许我在这里继续前进，但请感受
Allow me to forge ahead here, but please feel
只要通过聊天就可以继续提问。
free to continue asking questions along the way if only via the chat.
现在让我们考虑如何改进这个程序。
Let's consider now how we might go about improving this program.
让我们来改进一下这个程序，使它更具有交互性
Let's go about improving this program to make it a little more interactive
而不是假设每个人都想被欢迎
and not just assume that everyone is going to want to be greeted
更通俗地说就是“你好，世界”。
more generically as hello, world.
看看我能不能让这个程序说出“你好，大卫”这样的话
Let's see if I can't get this program to say something like Hello, David
或者 Hello Jeremiah 或者 Hello Horatio 或者其他用户的名字。
or Hello, Jeremiah or Hello, Horatio or whatever the actual user's name is.
为了做到这一点，我要回到“你好，圆周率”
Well to do this I'm going to go back up to Hello to pi
我要在最上面再加一行代码,
and I'm going to add another line of code at the very top that simply says,
比如，你叫什么名字，引号后面多加一个空格。
for instance, what's your name, quote unquote with an extra space at the end.
所以我打印给用户询问他们一些输入的问题,
So I'm printing to the user asking them a question for some input,
但现在我需要另一个函数来实际获取用户的输入。
but now I need another function to actually get input from the user.
而且，完美的是，足够多的 Python 附带了一个名为 input 的函数。
And, perfectly, enough Python comes with a function named input.
这里我要调用一个函数输入打开括号,
So here I'm going to go ahead and call a function input, open paren,
关闭括号。
close paren.
这将提示用户只有一个闪烁的光标在等待
And that's going to prompt the user with just a blinking cursor waiting
让他们输入一些东西。
for them to type something in.
结果是，如果我读了输入函数的文档,
Now it turns out, if I read the documentation for the input function,
它实际上需要一个论点本身。
it actually takes an argument itself.
我不需要单独使用“ print”然后提示用户输入。
I don't need to use "print" separately and then prompt the user for input.
所以我可以在使用代码之前就简化它。
So I can actually simplify this code before we even use it.
我要继续从 print 中取出同样的字符串,
I'm going to go ahead here and take that same string from print,
把它作为输入函数的参数,
put it as an argument to the input function,
把“指纹”一起去掉。
and get rid of the "print" altogether.
而且，事实上，“ print”本来也会添加一行新的内容。
And, in fact, that "print" would have added a new line anyway.
现在我得到了用户光标所在的提示符
So now I've just got a prompt where the user's cursor is
最后会眨眼问他们，你叫什么名字？
going to end up blinking at the end of the line asking them, what's your name?
在终端窗口中，我将运行 Python of Hello.py，Enter。
In my terminal window I'm going to run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
好的。
OK.
我们有进展了。
We're making progress.
似乎这个新的函数输入确实提示我，人类,
It seems that this new function input is indeed prompting me, the human,
输入。
for input.
我要输入我的名字
So I'm going to type in my name--
大卫——然后按回车键。
David-- and hit Enter.
不幸的是，这和我的名字没什么关系,
Unfortunately, it doesn't really do anything with my name,
它只是立即输出它。
it just outputs it immediately.
好吧，我能搞定的，对吧？
All right, well, I could fix this, right?
我可以去2行把“ world”改成“ David”
I could go up to line 2 and I could change "world" to "David,"
然后回到我的终端窗口，在这里我可以做 Python 的 Hello.py，Enter。
and then back in my terminal window here I can do Python of Hello.py, Enter.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
大卫，进来。
David, Enter.
好了。
And there we go.
好了，现在我可以开始工作了。
All right now I'm up and running.
现在我的程序正在按预期运行。
Now my program is working as intended.
当然，这不是真正的工作原理。
Of course, this isn't really working as intended here.
让我继续假装是我的同事 Carter。
Let me go ahead and try pretending to be my colleague, Carter here.
卡特的名字是这样的。
Well Carter's name is this.
我现在要按回车，然后我会看到，当然，你好，卡特
I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter and I'll see, of course, Hello, Carter--
显然不是，因为我已经硬编码了，可以这么说,
well, obviously not, because I've hardcoded, so to speak,
我已经把我的名字写在字符串里了。
I've written literally my name inside of the string.
所以我们现在需要一些方法来实际得到用户的输入是什么
So we need some way now of actually getting back what the user's input is
并最终用它做些事情。
and doing something with it ultimately.
为此我们将利用编程的另一个特性,
And for this we're going to leverage another feature of programming,
特别是某些函数的一个特性，那就是它们
specifically a feature of some functions, which is that they
也可以有返回值。
can have return values as well.
如果你再次把输入看作是这个动作,
If you think of input as being, again, this action,
这个动词，你可以把它拟人化为一个人,
this verb-- you can actually personify it as maybe a person,
就像你的一个朋友，你问了一个问题
like a friend of yours that you've asked a question of
你让你的朋友去找别人帮忙
and you've asked your friend to go get input from someone else--
去问那个人他们的名字。
go ask that person their name.
如果你的朋友回来时知道了那个人的名字,
And if your friend comes back knowing that person's name, well,
如果他们把那个名字还给你不是很好吗？
wouldn't it be nice if they handed that name back to you?
这就是我们需要的隐喻功能,
That's kind of what we need metaphorically the function to do,
就是获取用户的输入，然后交还给我，这样我这个程序员,
is get the user's input and then hand it back to me so that I, the programmer,
可以做点什么。
can do something with it.
但如果要还给我,
But if it's going to be handed back to me,
我想把它放在某个地方这样我就可以把它打印出来了
I kind of want to put it somewhere so that I can then print it back
在屏幕上。
on the screen.
我需要做相当于拿出一张纸或便利贴,
I need to do the equivalent of take out like a piece of paper or Post-It note,
在这张纸上写下人类所说的话,
write down on this piece of paper what it is the human has said,
这样我就可以把它输入到打印函数中。
so that I can then feed it into as input that print function.
要做到这一点，我们还需要一个编程特性，即
And to do that, we're going to need one more feature of programming, namely
变量。
variables.
而且很有可能，大多数人都熟悉数学课上的变量
And odds are, most everyone's familiar with variables from math class
很久以前，x，y，z 之类的。
way back when-- x and y and z and the like.
编程也有同样的能力，这种能力
Well, programming has that same capability, this ability
创建一个变量——在这个例子中，在计算机的内存中——
to create a variable-- in this case, in the computer's memory--
而不是一张纸。
not just on a piece of paper.
这个变量可以存储一个值
And that variable can store a value--
一个数字，一些文字，甚至一个图像或视频或更多。
a number, some text, even an image or video or more.
变量只是计算机内部某个值的容器
A variable is just a container for some value inside of a computer
或者在你自己的程序里。
or inside of your own program.
那么，我该如何用这种方式表达自己呢？
So how do I go about expressing myself in this way?
我想我要做的就是介绍
Well I think what I'm going to do is introduce
一个比 x 或 y 更有趣的变量。
a variable that's a little more interestingly named than x or y.
我可以这样说—— x = input。
I could just say this-- x = input.
但我要用一个比典型的数学变量更好的名字
But I'm going to use a better name than a typical mathematical variable here
为什么我要称变量为“ name”呢？
and I'm going to literally call my variable "name," why?
在编程方面，因为我面前有一整个键盘,
Well in programming, because I have a whole keyboard in front of me,
我可以用更多的描述性术语来描述我正在写的东西。
I can use more descriptive terms to describe what it is I'm writing.
但是现在，我们有机会考虑一个特定的语法。
And now, though, there's an opportunity to consider a specific piece of syntax.
我们看过括号，我们看过引号，所有这些
We've seen parentheses, we've seen quotes, all of which
在传递输入到函数时是必需的,
are necessary when passing inputs to a function,
但这个等号在右边的输入和名字之间
but this equal sign here that's in between input on the right and name
实际上是很重要的。
on the left is actually important.
严格来说，这不是一个等号。
And it's technically not an equal sign per se.
与其说它意味着相等，不如说它意味着赋值。
It doesn't mean equality as much as it means assignment.
所以在 Python 和许多编程语言中,
So in Python and many programming languages,
单个等号是赋值运算符
a single equal sign is the assignment operator
具体的意思是，你
and what that means specifically is that, you
无论用户的输入是什么，都要从右向左分配。
want to assign from right to left whatever the user's input is.
所以无论返回值是多少，等号都是从右向左复制的
So the equal sign copies from the right to the left whatever the return
右边函数的值是。
value of the function on the right is.
因此，输入函数显然是从用户那里获得输入的。
So again, the input function clearly gets input from the user.
这就是为什么我能输入我的名字或者卡特的，但是
That's why I was able to type my name or Carter's, but it also
在幕后把值，返回值传递给我
sort of behind the scenes hands that value, that return value, back to me
程序员。
the programmer.
如果我用一个等号和一个变量不管我怎么称呼它,
And if I use an equal sign and a variable, no matter what I call it,
我可以将输入存储在该变量中，以便以后重用它。
I can store that input in that variable so as to reuse it later.
所以现在，坐在电脑内存的某个地方,
So now, sitting in the computer's memory somewhere,
是一个包含“大卫”报价，引号或“卡特”报价的容器,
is a container containing "David" quote, unquote or "Carter" quote,
或者其他人类输入的东西。
unquote, or whatever the human has typed in.
但在这里很容易出错。
But here it's easy to make a mistake.
假设我决定尝试打印这个名称等等
Suppose I decide to try to print that name and so
我有种直觉，你好，名字。
I kind of on a hunch type in this, hello, name.
只是插入了变量的名称。
Just kind of plugging in the name of the variable.
让我继续运行 Python of Hello.py 并点击 Enter。
Well let me go ahead here and run Python of Hello.py and hit Enter.
这会让我想起自己的名字。
That's going to prompt me for my name.
让我输入我的名字
And let me type in my name--
D-A-V-I-D 但我还没按回车键。
D-A-V-I-D. But I haven't hit Enter yet.
也许通过聊天，当我现在点击回车时会发生什么？
And perhaps via the chat, what's going to happen here when I now hit Enter?
我希望它说，你好，大卫。
I'm hoping it says, Hello, David.
如果上面写的是“你好，世界”我没意见，但我不想让它写出实际情况
I'd be OK if it says Hello, world, but I don't want it to say what it's actually
会说，是的，我们在聊天中看到的是,
going to say and, yep, what we're seeing in the chat is,
可能是字面上的“你好，名字”。
well, it's probably going to say literally Hello, name.
所以这并不完全正确。
So that's not quite right.
所以我们需要另一种方法来打印出变量内部的值
So we need another way of printing out the value inside of that variable
而不是“名字”这个词
rather than just this word "name."
让我用几种不同的方法来试试。
Well let me try this in a couple of different ways.
让我试试这样——
Let me try this as follows--
让我继续，也许可以撤销这个，因为我已经做得很好了
let me go ahead and maybe undo this because I've gotten pretty good already
打招呼。
at saying Hello.
所以让我们划清界限，然后说，好吧,
So let's draw that line in the sand and just say, all right,
我们至少把 Hello 逗号弄出去吧。
let's get at least get Hello comma out the door.
现在打印姓名，凭直觉，我要试试这个。
Let's now print name and just on a hunch, I'm going to try this.
我要再次使用指纹
I'm going to use print again--
因为你可以根据需要使用这些函数
because you can use these functions as many times as you need--
我要把名为 name 的变量传递给 print 函数。
and I'm going to pass to the print function the variable called name.
但是注意我现在有点聪明了。
But notice I'm being a little clever now.
我不会把它放在双引号里，因为我们已经看过那个双引号了
I'm not putting it in double quotes because we've seen already that double
引号的意思是字面上打印出 N-A-M-E。
quotes means literally print out N-A-M-E.
这次我要删掉引用，希望,
I'm getting rid of the quotes this time in hopes that,
现在，通过将名为 name 的变量传递给名为 print 的函数,
now by passing the variable called name to the function called print it will,
实际上，打印这个变量的内容,
in fact, go about printing the contents of that variable that is,
所谓的价值。
its so-called value.
好吧，我们就在这里开始吧。
All right, let's go ahead and do this here.
Python of Hello.py，Enter.
Python of Hello.py, Enter.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
大卫。
David.
现在，我仍然祈祷，我看到你好逗号大卫。
And now, crossing my fingers still, I see Hello comma David.
好吧。
All right.
所以这不是最好的项目。
So it's not the best program.
可以这么说，我在走捷径。
I'm kind of cutting some corners here, so to speak.
我说你好，大卫，在两条不同的线路上。
I'm saying Hello, David on two separate lines.
所以它不够优雅，不够漂亮,
So it's not as elegant, it's not as pretty,
它在英语中的语法不像说出来那么恰当
it's not as grammatically appropriate in English as just saying it
都在同一条线上，但至少我解决了问题，只是没有
all in one breath on one line, but at least I've solved the problem, just not
非常好。
very well yet.
但是现在让我退一步，也许介绍一下
But let me take a step back now and perhaps introduce
还有一些我们应该熟悉的概念,
a couple of other concepts with which we should be familiar,
这是因为我们的程序越来越长，它们不再只是一行或两行
which is as our programs get longer and they're no longer just one line or two
甚至三个，最终我们的程序会变成几十行,
or even three, eventually our programs are going to become dozens of lines,
甚至可能有几百行。
maybe even hundreds of lines long.
让我们为未来的成功做好准备。
Let's set the stage for success moving forward.
事实证明，Python 和许多编程语言
It turns out that Python and a lot of programming languages
也支持一种叫做评论的东西。
also support something called comments.
注释是代码中对自己的注释
Comments are notes to yourself in your code
并且通过一个特殊的符号(在 Python 中)包含注释
and you include comments by way of a special symbol-- in Python
通常是散列符号
it's going to be the hash symbol, typically--
这样你就可以写出等价的
and that allows you to write the equivalent
给你自己的一个音符，但在某种程度上，不会打破你的代码。
of a note to yourself but in a way that's not going to break your code.
计算机实际上忽略了你的评论。
The computer actually ignores your comment.
它就在你身边，它就在你的老师身边,
It's just there for you, it's just there for your teacher,
只是为你的同事准备的
it's just there for your colleague with whom
你最终会分享那些代码。
you're sharing ultimately that code.
所以如果我回到 VS 码这里
So if I go back to VS Code here and I just
我想给这个节目添加一些评论，向我的老师解释,
want to add some comments to this program to explain to my teacher,
告诉我自己，告诉我的同事这个项目在做什么,
to myself, to my colleagues what this program is doing,
那我们就这么做吧。
well, let's go ahead and do that.
我将从程序的最顶端开始，在第1行
I'm going to go at the very top of my program and on line 1
现在我要把原始代码行往下移一点,
now I'm going to move that original line of code down a bit,
我要加一个散列，然后这样说,
I'm going to add a hash, and I'm going to say something like this,
向用户询问他们的名字。
ask user for their name.
现在，我不需要用那种语言。
Now, I don't have to use that language.
我没必要用那条短信。
I don't have to use that text.
我可以使用任何人类的语言。
I could use any human language whatsoever.
不一定非得是英语。
It doesn't have to be English.
但我现在要说的是，在这下面，就像这样说
But I'm going to now, below that, just say something like this--
向用户问好。
say Hello to user.
你会注意到默认的 VS 代码
And you'll notice that VS Code by default
让我的评论都变灰了。
is kind of graying out my comments.
它们不再是蓝色的，没有红色，没有颜色。
They're no longer blue, there's no red, there's no color in them.
那只是因为它们是我的笔记
And that's just because they're notes to myself
计算机最终会忽略它们。
and the computer ultimately is going to ignore them.
但是我们现在有两条评论——问用户
But what we have now is two comments-- ask user
为他们的名字，然后第二个评论，说你好用户。
for their name and then a second comment, say Hello to user.
我给每段代码都加了注释,
And I've just kind of commented each chunk of code,
就像每一行或每一行代码的复数，它们都在做一些值得注意的事情。
like each line or lines plural of code, that are doing something noteworthy.
为什么？
Why?
明天早上我醒来的时候
Well, tomorrow morning when I wake up having
睡了很长一段时间，忘记了我前一天做了什么,
slept for quite some time, forgotten what it is I did the previous day,
看到评论很方便
it's convenient with comments to just see
在英语或你自己的人类语言什么
in English or your own human language what
这个程序这样做是为了让你不必去读代码本身
it is this program is doing so that you don't have to read the code itself
更好的是，如果以后出了什么差错,
and, better yet, if there's maybe a mistake down the road,
你可以读你的意图是什么，然后你可以看代码
you can read what your intention was and then you can look at the code
并确定您的代码现在是否正在执行您想要的操作。
and figure out if your code is now doing what you intended.
所以对于这么小的程序来说，这是不必要的。
So this isn't really necessary for a program this small.
只要一两三句台词就很明显了
It's pretty obvious with just one or two or three lines
程序在做什么。
what the program is doing.
读代码和读注释一样快,
It's just as fast to read the code than the comments,
但是养成这个习惯通常是件好事
but getting into this habit is generally a good thing--
每隔一行或几行注释代码，以提醒自己
to comment your code every one or a few lines so as to remind yourself
而其他人则知道您的意图和代码正在做什么。
and others what it is your intent and your code is doing.
评论的好处也在于——
What's nice about comments too is this--
评论也可以成为你的待办事项清单。
comments can also serve to be sort of a to-do list for yourself.
在伪代码编程中有这样一个概念。
There's this notion in programming of pseudocode.
伪代码不是一个正式的东西。
Pseudocode isn't a formal thing.
这不是一种特定的语言。
It's not one specific language.
只是用英语或者你自己的人类语言
It's just using English or your own human language
简洁有条不紊地用算法表达你的想法,
to express your thoughts succinctly, methodically, algorithmically,
可以这么说。
so to speak.
但是伪代码，因此，因为它不是 Python
But pseudocode, therefore, because it's not Python
不一定是英语，只是允许
and it's not necessarily English, it just kind of allows
你甚至要提前概述你的计划。
you to outline your program even in advance.
举个例子，如果我今天不确定
So for instance, if I wasn't sure today how
我想写这个程序
I wanted to go about writing this program
但我不知道我想做什么，我可以今天就开始
but I didn't know what I wanted to do, I could have started today
用 Hello.py 写下来。
by just writing this in Hello.py.
没有代码，我可以只给自己写几条注释——
No code, I could have written just a couple of comments to myself--
步骤1，询问用户的名称。
Step 1, ask user for their name.
步骤2，向用户说 Hello。
Step 2, say Hello to user.
一旦我用伪代码概述了我的程序，我就可以进去了
Then once I've outlined my program in pseudocode, then I can go in there
然后说，好吧，我怎么问用户他们的名字？
and say, all right, how do I ask the user for their name?
我可以输入“你叫什么名字”的问题？
Well, I can do input "what's your name" question?
然后在左边这里，我可以放一个变量并赋值给它。
And then on the left here, I can maybe put a variable and assign it to that.
好的，我如何对用户说 Hello？
OK, how do I say Hello to the user?
我知道我可以用印刷品在屏幕上说话。
Well, I know I can use print to say things on the screen.
让我打个招呼，让我..
Let me say hello, and let me--
好的，现在打印这个人的名字。
OK, let me now print the person's name.
因此，伪代码是构造待办事项列表的一种很好的方法,
So again, pseudocode is a nice way of structuring your to-do list,
特别是如果你不知道如何编写代码,
especially if you have no idea how to write the code,
因为它把一个更大的程序分解成小的任务。
because it breaks a bigger program down into small bite-sized tasks.
好吧，让我暂停一下，看看现在有没有
All right, let me pause here to see if there are now
关于注释、伪代码、返回值或变量的任何问题。
any questions on comments, pseudocode, return values, or variables.
有什么问题要问清楚吗？
Any questions we can clear up here?
观众: 是的，我的问题是函数输入
AUDIENCE: Yeah, my question is does the function input
为任何类型的信息工作，还是只为文字？
work for any type of information, or only for words?
大卫. 马兰: 是的，真是个好问题。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, really good question.
因此，根据它的文档，我们将看到更多的正式文档
So according to its documentation, and we'll look more at formal documentation
很快，输入将期待所谓的
soon, input is going to expect what's called
一个字符串，即一个文本序列
a string, that is a sequence of text, be it
用英语或任何其他人类语言。
in English or any other human language.
但是它确实需要用文本来提示用户。
But it's indeed going to be expecting text with which to prompt the user.
问得好。
A good question.
如果可以的话，大家再问一个问题怎么样？
How about another question from the group, if we could?
观众: 我想知道我该如何做几行评论？
AUDIENCE: I wanted to ask how would I make a several line comment?
大卫. 马兰: 哦，你是怎么写很多评论的,
DAVID MALAN: Oh, how do you do many lines of comments,
我没听错吧？
if I'm hearing you correctly?
观众: 是的。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
当然。
DAVID MALAN: Sure.
你会一直这样下去。
You would just keep doing them like this.
你只需要在每一行前面加上一个散列符号，就像我在这里做的一样。
You just prefix each of the lines with a hash symbol, like I'm doing here.
在 Python 中还有另一种用于执行多行注释的技术
There is another technique for doing multi-line comments in Python that
实际上往往有特殊的意义。
actually tend to have special meaning.
你可以像这样做三个双引号，然后在这里之间的任何东西
You can do three double quotes like this and then anything in between here
是一个评论。
is a comment.
这是另一种技巧。
That's another technique.
或者你也可以使用单引号。
Or you can use single quotes as well.
下次再说吧。
But more on those, I think, another time.
好吧，如果你不介意的话，我先走了
All right, well, you don't mind, let me forge ahead here
看看我们如何进一步改进这个项目
and see how we might improve this program further
同时也介绍了一些其他的特性
and also introduce a few other features that we might
要考虑到随着时间的推移。
want to take into account over time.
所以我们可以改进这个程序
So it turns out that we can certainly improve on this program
因为我要抄近路有点失望
because it's a little disappointing that I'm cutting this corner
然后说 Hello 逗号，然后在新行上打印出名称。
and saying Hello comma and then on a new line printing out name.
好像我们能做得更好似的。
Like we can do better.
当然，你在手机或笔记本电脑上使用的大多数程序也是如此
And most programs you use on your phone or your laptop certainly
当人们需要的时候保持短信在一起。
keep text together when people want.
那我们该怎么做呢？
So how can we go about doing that?
有几种不同的方法。
Well there's a few different ways.
事实上，我们的目标并不是解决这个问题,
And in fact, the goal here is not so much to solve this one problem,
而是在编程中证明和强调这一点
but to demonstrate and emphasize that in programming--
Python 和其他语言，有很多方法
Python and other languages-- there's so many ways
有时是为了解决同一个问题。
sometimes to solve the same problem.
这里有一个解决这个问题的方法。
And here's one way to solve this problem.
让我进去打个招呼,
Let me go in here and let me go ahead now and say hello,
让我把用户名添加到末尾。
and let me just add to the end of that the user's name.
所以我以一种有趣的方式使用 + 。
So I'm using + in kind of an interesting way.
这本身不是加法。
This is not addition, per se.
我当然不会加数字，但我会
I'm not adding numbers, obviously, but I do
想要将人名添加到文本 Hello 逗号的字符串中。
kind of want to add the person's name to the string of text Hello comma.
现在让我下到我的终端窗口，运行 Python of Hello.py
Well let me go now down to my terminal window and run Python of Hello.py
再一次，回车。
again, Enter.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
我要输入大卫。
I'm going to type in David.
进来。
Enter.
好了，好多了。
OK, it's better.
好多了，但有个小问题，虽然很美观。
It's better, but there's a minor bug, albeit aesthetic here.
这里缺少空间，但我们还是用直觉吧。
There's missing space, but let's just use some intuition here.
如果我漏掉了逗号后面的空格,
Well, if I'm missing the space after the comma,
我为什么不直接手动添加到这里呢。
why don't I go ahead and just add it manually here.
现在让我重新运行 Hello.py、 Enter、 David、 Enter 的 Python 程序。
Let me now rerun the program Python of Hello.py, Enter, David, Enter.
好了。
And there we go.
现在我们有了更漂亮的东西
Now we have something that looks a little prettier
在英语语法方面。
in terms of English grammar.
你好，逗号，空格，大卫。
Hello, comma, space, David.
现在如果我们倒回去，你可能已经注意到了
And now if we rewind, you might have noticed before
或者想知道为什么在我的问号后面有这么多空间,
or wondered why I had this seemingly extra space after my question mark,
也就是这里。
namely here.
在问号之后，双引号之前有个空格
There's a space after the question mark but before the double quote
这也只是为了美学。
and that was just for aesthetics too.
我希望将用户的光标向右移动一个空格
I wanted to move the user's cursor one space to the right
所以当我输入他们的名字或者他们输入他们的名字时,
so that when I typed their name or they typed their name,
并不是紧挨着那个问号。
it's not immediately next to that same question mark there.
但我们还有别的办法。
But there's other ways we can do this.
有些函数，在它们之间打印,
It turns out that some functions, print among them,
实际上采取多个论点。
actually take multiple arguments.
结果表明，如果你把输入分开
And it turns out that if you separate the inputs
函数的所谓参数用逗号表示,
to a function-- the so-called arguments to a function-- with a comma,
你不仅可以进去一个，还可以进去两个，三个，四个，五个。
you can pass in not just one, but two, three, four, five, onward.
所以让我继续传入，不仅仅是 hello，逗号，space，还有接下来的
So let me go ahead and pass in not just hello, comma, space, but that followed
名字。
by name.
乍一看，这有点让人困惑
And this is a little confusing potentially at first glance
因为现在我有两个逗号，但是要注意
because now I've got two commas but it's important to note
第一个逗号在我的引号里面，这很简单
that the first comma is inside of my quotation marks, which is simply
英语语法的东西。
an English grammatical thing.
这里的第二个逗号在引号之外,
The second comma here is outside of the quotes,
而是在现在两个要打印的独立参数之间。
but between what are now two separate arguments to print.
第一个参数是 hello，逗号，space。
The first argument is hello, comma, space.
第二个参数是 name 变量本身。
The second argument is the name variable itself.
我们来看看效果如何。
So let's see how this looks.
Python of Hello.py，Enter.
Python of Hello.py, Enter.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
大卫。
David.
进来。
Enter.
好吧，我有点矫枉过正了。
OK, I've kind of over-corrected.
出于某种原因，我现在有两个空格。
Now I've got two spaces for some reason.
事实证明，这很微妙
Well, it turns out, and this is subtle, when
传递多个要打印的参数时，它会自动为您插入一个空格。
you pass multiple arguments to print, it automatically inserts a space for you.
之前没有关系，因为我有
This was not relevant earlier because I was
传入一个大参数，通过使用 + 运算符一次打印所有参数。
passing in one big argument to print all at once by using that + operator.
因为逗号的缘故，这次我用了两个。
This time I'm passing in two because of the comma.
所以如果我不想要额外的空间，我也不需要自己通过,
So if I don't want that extra space, I don't need to pass in one myself,
我可以这样做，现在注意，如果我再次运行这个程序——
I can just do this and now notice, if I run this program again--
Python of Hello.py 输入我的名字 David,
Python of Hello.py, type in my name David,
现在语法上看起来像是我想要的。
now it looks grammatically like I might want.
那么，这些方法中哪一种更好呢？
Now which of these approaches is better?
这种方法使用带有两个参数的函数 print ——
This approach uses a function print with two arguments--
你好，逗号和 name 变量。
Hello, comma and the name variable.
前一个版本，回忆，技术上使用了一个参数,
The previous version, recall, technically used one argument,
虽然看起来有点奇怪。
even though it looked a little curious.
从某种意义上说，计算机就像数学家一样,
It's one argument in the sense that the computer, just like mathematicians,
首先要做括号里面的事。
are going to do what's inside of parentheses first.
所以如果在括号内有一串文本
So if inside of parentheses you have this string of text--
你好，逗号，还有一个空格，我要把它加回去。
hello, comma, and a space, which I need to add back.
然后你有一个 + ，这意味着本质上不是加法,
Then you have a +, which means not addition, per se,
而是连接——连接左边的东西和右边的东西。
but concatenation-- to join the thing on the left and the thing on the right.
这最终变成了英语短语——
This ultimately becomes the English phrase--
你好，逗号，空格，大卫。
Hello, comma, space, David.
然后最终传递给函数的
And then what's being passed ultimately to the function
技术上是这样的，但它是动态的。
is technically something like this, but it's doing it all dynamically.
不是我像之前那样小心翼翼地输入 David。
It's not me typing in David as I discreetly did earlier.
它将在连接 Hello 之后动态地计算出该值是什么
It's figuring out dynamically what that value is after concatenating Hello
然后最终传递它
with the value of name and then passing that ultimately
作为唯一参数打印。
to print as the sole argument.
让我暂停一下，看看有没有关于参数数量的问题
Let me pause here to see if there's any questions on numbers of arguments
现在开始工作。
now to functions.
观众: 我们可以多次使用一个函数吗
AUDIENCE: Can we use a function many times
解决一个我们在代码中可能会遇到很多次的问题？
to solve a certain problem which we can encounter many times in our code?
你可以的。
DAVID MALAN: You can.
你可以多次使用一个函数来解决一些问题。
You can use a function many different times to solve some problem.
不过，我们很快就会看到，如果你发现自己
What we'll soon see, though, is if you find yourself
作为程序员再次用同样的方法解决问题,
as the programmer solving a problem the same way again,
一次又一次，事实证明
and again, and again, it turns out you'll
能够使你自己的功能，使你
be able to make your own function so that you
不必重复使用随语言而来的基本内容。
don't have to keep reusing the basic ones that come with the language.
观众: 我对逗号和 + 号很好奇。
AUDIENCE: I was curious about the comma and the + sign.
在 + 符号之后，我们可以给出一个变量，在逗号之后
So after + sign, can we give just one variable and after comma again we
给多变量状态？
give multiple variable status?
有什么区别吗？
What is the difference?
问得好。
DAVID MALAN: A good question.
所以在字符串的上下文中
So in the context of strings--
我一直在用这个词。
and I keep using that term.
“字符串”是编程语言中的一个技术术语
"String" is a technical term in a programming language
同样，它意味着一个文本序列——一个字符，一个词，整个段落,
and again, it means a sequence of text-- a character, a word, a whole paragraph,
甚至。
even.
所以 + 运算符不仅仅是被使用，就像我们将要
So the + operator is not just used, as we'll
看，在 Python 中加入数字，就像我们在纸笔上做的那样,
see, for addition of numbers in Python, like we do on paper pencil,
但它也用于串联字符串的左侧和右侧。
but it also is used for concatenation of strings on the left and the right.
如果您确实想要组合不仅仅是两个字符串——
If you did want to combine not just two strings--
左边和右边，但是第三个和第四个,
left and right-- but a third and a fourth,
你完全可以继续使用 + ，+ ，+ ，然后把它们链接在一起
you can absolutely keep using +, +, +, +, and chain them together
就像数学一样。
just like in math.
最终会变得有点丑陋,
Eventually that's going to start to look a little ugly,
我敢说，特别是你的代码行太长的时候。
I dare say, especially if your line of code gets long.
所以我们很快就会看到更好的方法。
So there's better ways that we'll actually soon see.
也是个好问题。
And a good question as well.
让我们回到这里讨论的代码
Well let me come back to the code here in question
看看我们能不能给你展示一些其他的方法
and see if we can show you just a couple of other ways
解决同样的问题，同时强调我们在技术上
to solve the same problem, along the way emphasizing that what we're technically
在这里说，是的，有弦，但是有偶数
talking about here, yes, are strings, but there's even
在 Python 中这些字符串的技术术语,
a technical term for these strings in Python,
它只是 STR，可以这么说，简称为 S-T-R，字符串的缩写。
it's just STR, so to speak, S-T-R for short, for string.
你可能知道如果你用其他语言编程,
As you may know if you programmed in other languages,
发明编程语言的人喜欢简洁明了,
people who invent programming languages like to be very succinct, to the point,
所以我们倾向于用相当短的词组来描述事物,
so we tend to use fairly short phrases to describe things,
不一定是完整的词。
not necessarily full words.
虽然你可能会说“字符串”，技术上来说
So while you might say "string," technically
在 Python 中我们真正讨论的是这些文本序列,
in Python what we're really talking about, these sequences of text,
严格来说是 STR。
are technically STRs.
这是程序中实际的数据类型。
This is an actual type of data in a program.
但是我们很快就会看到程序中还有其他类型的数据。
But we'll soon see that there's other types of data in programs as well.
事实上，让我们看看我们是否可以用另一种方法来改进它。
In fact, let's see if we can't improve this in one other way.
我喜欢我们在保持一致方面所取得的进展
I like the progress we've made by keeping everything on the same line--
你好，大卫都在同一条线上。
Hello, David all on the same line.
在解决这个问题方面，我们还能做些什么呢？
What more though could we do in terms of solving this problem?
事实证明我们没必要完全放弃
Well, it turns out that we didn't have to give up entirely
使用打印两次。
with using print twice.
让我倒带一下，回到之前的版本
Let me rewind a little bit and go back to that earlier version
我不确定如何解决这个问题所以我只用了一次 print
where I wasn't really sure how to solve this problem so I was using print once
打印出 Hello，空格和逗号。
to print out just the Hello and the space and the comma.
然后我又用 print 来打印名字。
And then I used print again to print name.
严格来说，这还不错，但是有一个视觉副作用
That's, strictly speaking, wasn't bad, but there was this visual side effect
我不喜欢的。
that I didn't like.
把这两行文字分开看起来很难看
It just looked ugly to have these two lines of text separate
彼此之间的联系。
from one another.
但还有别的办法解决这个问题。
But there's another way to fix this.
显然，打印函数似乎是自动的
Clearly it seems to be the case that the print function is automatically
输出一行空白。
outputting a blank line.
它会自动将光标移动到下一行
It's moving the cursor automatically for me to the next line
因为这就是为什么我在一条线上看到 Hello 和 David
because that's why I'm seeing Hello on one line and David
然后我的提示
on the next and then my prompt--
美元符号，在那下面的线上。
the dollar sign-- on the line below that.
所以印刷似乎是自动推测出来的
So print seems to be presuming automatically
您希望它将光标移动到下一行
that you want it to move the cursor to the next line
在你通过一些论点之后。
after you pass it some argument.
但你可以改变这种行为。
But you can override that behavior.
同样，函数采用影响其行为的参数,
Again, functions take arguments which influence their behavior,
你只需要知道那些论点是什么。
you just have to know what those arguments are.
结果是，如果我们查看 Python 打印的文档
And it turns out that if we look at the documentation for Python's print
函数，我们可以在这里查看这个 URL
function, we can actually look up at this URL here--
Python.org 是所有 Python 官方文档的所在地。
docs.python.org is where all of Python's official documentation lies.
如果我四处查看，我可以找到我的方式，更具体地说，这个网址
If I poke around, I can find my way to more specifically this URL
在这里我可以找到 Python 中所有可用的函数
here where I can find all of the available functions in Python
以及那里的文件。
and the documentation there for.
如果我再精确一点，我甚至可以
And if I go a little more precisely, I can even
查找打印功能本身的具体文档。
find specific documentation for the print function itself.
与其在浏览器里查看,
And rather than pull that up in a browser,
接下来我要突出显示同一个 URL 中的一行
I'm going to go ahead and highlight just one line from that same URL, which
这是我们见过的最神秘的东西,
is this, and this is easily the most cryptic thing we've seen yet,
但这是打印功能的官方文件。
but this is the official documentation for the print function.
这是学习编程语言时能做的最好的事情之一
And one of the best things you can do when learning a programming language
老实说，学会阅读文档,
is, honestly, learn to read the documentation,
因为事实上，你所有问题的答案都会以某种方式
because truly, all of the answers to your questions will in some way
即使，不可否认，这并不总是显而易见的。
be there, even though, admittedly, it's not always obvious.
我还要说，巨蟒的文档
And I will say too, Python's documentation
不一定是最简单的事情，尤其是对于初学者或新手
isn't necessarily the easiest thing, especially for a first time or novice
程序员。
programmer.
这也只是需要练习，所以如果你不是，尽量不要感到不知所措
It too just takes practice, so try not to get overwhelmed if you're not
确定你在看什么。
sure what you're looking at.
让我来给你们讲一下这个例子。
But let me walk you through this example.
这也是 Python 官方文档中的一行文本
This again is a line of text from Python's official documentation
打印功能。
for the print function.
这表示的是这样的——
What this indicates as follows is this--
这个函数的名称当然是 print。
the name of this function is, of course print.
这里有一个括号，另一个紧密的括号
Then there's a parenthesis over here and another close parenthesis way
在那边。
over there.
括号里的所有东西都是
Everything inside of those parentheses are
函数的参数，潜在参数。
the arguments, the potential arguments, to the function.
但是，当我们看到这些论点的时候
However, when we're looking at these arguments
在这样的文档中，技术上有一个不同的术语
in the documentation like this, there's technically a different term
我们会用到的。
that we would use.
从技术上讲，这些是函数的参数。
These are technically the parameters to the function.
所以当你讨论可以传递给函数的内容时
So when you're talking about what you can pass to a function
这些输入被称为参数。
and what those inputs are called, those are parameters.
当您实际使用函数并传递
When you actually use the function and pass
在这些括号里的值，这些输入,
in values inside of those parentheses, those inputs,
这些值都是参数。
those values are arguments.
所以我们讨论的是完全一样的东西——参数和参数
So we're talking about the exact same thing-- parameters and arguments are
实际上是一样的，但是你的条件
effectively the same thing, but the terms you
从不同的角度看问题。
use from looking at the problem from different directions.
当我们考虑函数能带走什么和什么的时候
When we're looking at what the function can take versus what
你实际上是在传递函数。
you're actually passing into the function.
那么这意味着什么呢？
So what does this imply?
这个语法很神秘，但是现在,
Well this syntax is pretty cryptic, but at the moment,
只要知道一个星号，一颗星星，然后“物体”这个词
just know that an asterisk, a star, and then the word "objects"
意味着打印函数可以接受任意数量的对象。
means that the print function can take any number of objects.
您可以传入0个字符串的文本，一个字符串
You can pass in 0 strings of text, one string
像我一样，两根弦像我一样，或者，技术上来说，无限多
like I did, two strings like I did, or, technically, infinitely many
如果你真的想，虽然这个代码看起来不会很好。
if you really want, though that code is not going to look very good.
之后我们看到一个逗号，然后我们看到另一个参数在这里
After that we see a comma, then we see another parameter here
称为「学校资讯科技教育自评系统」(SEP)。
called SEP, short for separator in English.
注意等号和单引号，空格，单引号。
And notice the equal sign and the single quote, space, single quote.
所以“太空”我还不知道那是什么,
So 'space' I don't know what that is yet,
但我想我们已经看到了暗示。
but I think we've seen a hint about it.
让我们把注意力集中在这上面
Let's focus though for a moment on this--
Print 函数接受另一个参数 end 和 default
the print function takes another parameter called end and the default
这个参数的值显然是基于这个等号和这些
value of that parameter is apparently, based on this equal sign and these
引用,/n。
quotes, /n.
什么是/n，如果你想在聊天中插话？
And what is /n, if you'd like to chime in in the chat?
任何有经验的程序员都可能见过这个,
Anyone who's program before has probably seen this,
不过如果你以前没有编过程序，这看起来可能很神秘。
though if you've never programmed before, this might look quite cryptic.
反斜杠 n 表示新行，这是一种文本方式
Backslash n means new line, and it's a way textually
指示是否以及何时需要有效地使用计算机
of indicating if and when you want the computer effectively
若要将光标移动到下一行，请创建一行新的文本。
to move the cursor to the next line, create a new line of text.
所以严格来说，如果我们仔细阅读文档,
And so technically, if we read into the documentation,
我们会看到更多细节。
we'll see more detail on this.
在打印文档中有一个名为 end 的参数
The fact that there's a parameter called end in the documentation for the print
函数，这意味着默认情况下，这个打印函数将结束
function, just means that by default this print function is going to end
以/n 开头的每一行。
every line with /n.
你看到的不是字面意义上的/n，而是一条新线。
You don't literally see /n, you see a new line.
可以看到光标移动到下一行。
You see the cursor moving to the next line.
按照这个逻辑，我们倒退一下。
Now by that logic, let's move backwards.
SEP 四个分隔符——分隔符的默认值
SEP four separator-- the default value of separator
显然是一个单一的空白空间。
is apparently a single blank space.
我们在哪儿见过？
Well where have we seen that?
回想一下之前的例子，我传入的不是一个，而是两个
Well recall in an earlier example when I passed in not just one but two
打印函数的参数。
arguments to the print function.
回想一下，他们之间神奇地有一个空间。
Recall that they magically had a space between them.
事实上，他们有那个空间 + 我自己的空间
In fact, they had that space + my own space
这就是为什么我删除了我的空间，因为那时它是额外的。
and that's why I deleted my space because at that point it was extra.
这意味着当你传递多个参数进行打印时，默认情况下
So this just means that when you pass multiple arguments to print, by default
它们将被一个单独的空间隔开。
they're going to be separated by a single space.
默认情况下，当传递要打印的参数时,
By default, when you pass arguments to print,
而是整个事情将以一个新台词结束。
it's the whole thing is going to be ended with a new line.
现在只要知道这一点，让我从字面上
Now just by knowing this, and let me literally
我对剩下的文件挥挥手，改天再说,
wave my hand at the rest of the documentation for another day,
还有更多的东西可以打印，但我们
there's more things that print can do, but we're
只关注 SEP 和 END，让我们看看我们现在是否可以利用这一点
going to focus just on SEP and on END, let's see if we can't leverage this now
来解决最初的问题。
to solve that original problem.
最初的问题是这样的，我不喜欢如何你好，大卫
The original problem was this, I don't like how Hello, David
在两条不同的线上。
is on two different lines.
这种情况又发生了，因为打印是自动的
Well that's happening again because print is automatically
打印出一条新线，所以我们告诉它不要这样做。
printing out a new line, so let's tell it not to do that.
让我们通过将第二个参数传递给第一次使用 PRINT 来说明这一点
Let's tell it by passing a second argument to the first use of PRINT
表示 END = quote，unquote ——
to say END = quote, unquote--
Not/n，这是默认值。
not /n, which is the default automatically.
让我们引用它，引用没有别的。
Let's make it quote, unquote nothing else.
让我们覆盖默认值，这样就没有新行了。
Let's override the default value so there is no new line.
那里什么都没有。
There's literally nothing there.
看看会发生什么。
And let's see what happens.
现在让我下到我的终端窗口，并清除它。
Let me now go down to my terminal window and clear it.
我将运行 Python of Hello.py，Enter。
And I'm going to run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
我要输入我的名字，大卫和我
I'm going to type in my name, David and I
我想现在一切都会保持原样，因为..
think now everything is going to stay on the same line because--
这一行，5，打印出 Hello，逗号，空格,
and it did-- this line here, 5, is going to print out Hello, comma, space,
但最后什么都没发生，因为我
but then nothing at the end of it because I
改成引号，引号。
changed it to be quote, unquote.
第二行是打印名字，大卫,
The second line is going to print the name, David,
或者不管人类的名字是什么，它会把光标移动到下一行
or whatever the human's name is, and it will move the cursor to the next line
因为我没有覆盖 END 的值。
because I didn't override the value of END there.
为了更清楚地看到这一点，如果你做一些神秘的事情，比如,
Just to see this more explicitly, if you do something cryptic like,
我不知道发生了什么。
well I have no idea what's going on.
让我暂时在这里打三个问号。
Let me just put in temporarily three question marks here.
我们也会看到结果的。
We'll see the results of this too.
让我回到我的终端窗口，运行 Python 的 hello. py,
Let me go back down to my terminal window, run Python of hello. py,
你叫什么名字？
what's your name?
大卫。
David.
现在你可以看到非常难看的输出,
And now you see literally really ugly output,
但你可以看到事情的真相。
but you see literally what's going on.
您好，逗号，空格，然后三个问号，END，打印语句,
Hello, comma, space, then three question marks, END, that print statement,
然后你会看到 D-A-V-I-D 所以这不是个好结果,
and then you see D-A-V-I-D. So not a good outcome,
但它也证明了我们在这里有多大的控制力。
but it demonstrates just how much control we have here too.
我再倒回去一点。
And let me rewind further.
回想一下，在我们的另一个版本中,
Recall that in our other version of this,
当我传入 Hello、逗号和 name 时，它们被一个空格隔开。
when I passed in Hello, comma and name, they were separated by a single space.
Python of Hello.py，D-A-V-I-D，Enter.
So Python of Hello.py, D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
成功了。
That just worked.
那么，如果我们覆盖分隔符的 SEP 值呢？
Well what if we override the value of SEP for separator?
我们可以说点什么，而不是一个空间
Instead of being one space, we could say something
就像，问号，问号，问号只是为了包装
like, question mark, question mark, question mark just to wrap
我们对那里发生了什么的想法。
our minds around what's going on there.
现在让我来做 Python of Hello.py，D-A-V-I-D，Enter。
Let me now do Python of Hello.py, D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
你看到两个。
And you see two.
这两个输入
These two inputs--
你好，逗号和名字现在以一种丑陋的方式分开了
Hello, comma and the name are now separated in an ugly way
因为我已经改写了「学校资讯科技教育自评系统」的预设行为。
by three question marks because I've overridden the default behavior of SEP.
即使文档使用单引号,
And even though the documentation uses single quotes,
我有使用双引号的习惯。
I've been in the habit of using double quotes.
在 Python 中，您可以使用。
In Python you can use either.
严格来说，这无关紧要，但你应该坚持
Strictly speaking, it doesn't matter, but you should be consistent
我通常使用双引号。
and I generally always use double quotes.
然而，Python 的文档总是使用单引号。
Python's documentation, though, always uses single quotes.
现在对这些类型的参数有什么问题吗？
Questions now on these types of parameters?
请允许我提议给它们正式命名。
And allow me to propose that we give these an official name.
到目前为止，我们一直在传递要打印的值,
Up until now, when we've been passing values to print,
这些被称为位置参数-在这个意义上的位置
those are called positional parameters-- positional in the sense
你传递给打印机的第一样东西会先打印出来。
that the first thing you pass to print gets printed first.
在第二次打印逗号之后传递给打印的第二个内容。
The second thing you pass to print after a comma gets printed second.
等等。
And so forth.
但是我们现在也看到了一些叫做命名参数的东西。
But there's also these things we've now seen called named parameters.
命名为 SEP，分隔符，或 END，E-N-D，表示行结束。
Named SEP, separator, or END, E-N-D for the line ending.
这些都是命名参数，因为第一，它们是可选的
Those are named parameters because one, they're optional
你可以在打印声明的末尾传递它们,
and you can pass them in at the end of your print statement,
但是你也可以通过名字来使用它们。
but you can also use them by name.
观众: 这可能是一个奇怪的问题，但我想知道,
AUDIENCE: This may be a weird question, but I was wondering,
如果有人想在引号中加上引号怎么办
what if someone wants to add actually quotation marks within the quotation
痕迹？
marks?
大卫. 马兰: 是的，我喜欢你的想法。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, I like how you think.
这就是我们所说的绝佳案例，对吧？
This is what we would call a corner case, right?
就在我们... 好了，就这些
Just when we've made-- right, this is all
听起来不错，至少在程序设计上是这样但是，等一下,
sounding great, at least as programming goes, but, wait a minute,
如果你想打印一个报价呢？
what if you want to print a quote?
问得好。
That's a really good question.
看看我们能不能解决这个问题。
Well, let's see if we can't figure this out.
假设我想打印出的不仅仅是用户名。
Suppose that I want to print out not just the user's name.
让我进一步简化一下。
Let me simplify this further.
让我先把这些东西处理掉,
Let me go ahead and get rid of a lot of this,
让我说几句，你好
and let me just say something like, Hello--
也许我是在讽刺你。
maybe I'm being a little sarcastic here.
你好，(讽刺地)“朋友”
Hello, (sarcastically) "friend."
就是那种语气。
You know, in that kind of tone.
事实上，这样是行不通的,
Well this is not going to work, actually,
因为你想用引号表示“朋友”
because you are trying to use quotes to be like "friend" in finger quotes,
但你也想结束这句话。
but you're also trying to end the sentence.
如果我试图运行这个，让我们做到这一点。
And if I try running this, let's do this.
Python，您将看到这只是无效的语法。
Python of Hello.py, you'll see that this is just invalid syntax.
也许你忘了一个逗号。
Perhaps you forgot a comma.
这其实有点烦人。
And this is actually a bit annoying.
有时，您看到的错误消息具有误导性。
Sometimes the error messages you see are misleading.
就像电脑，语言，并不是真的
Like the computer, the language, doesn't really
知道发生了什么，所以它会尽力而为
know what's going on so it gives its best
猜测，但不一定是正确的。
guess, but it's not necessarily correct.
但是我可以用几种方法来解决这个问题。
But I can solve this problem in a couple of ways.
我能做到
I can do this--
我可以把最外面的引号改成单引号。
I can change my outermost quotes to single quotes.
因为再回想一下，我说的是你
Because recall a moment again, I said you
可以使用双引号或单引号，只要你是一致的。
could use double quotes or single quotes so long as you're consistent.
所以没关系。
So that's fine.
如果在外部使用单引号，则
If you use single quotes on the outside, you
然后可以在内部使用双引号，你会看到他们的字面意思。
can then use double quotes on the inside and you'll see them literally.
例如，如果我运行 Python of Hello.py，就可以了。
So for instance, if I run Python of Hello.py, there we go.
你好，朋友
Hello, "friend."
但还有别的办法。
But there's another way.
如果你坚持使用双引号,
If you insist on using double quotes as you might want to,
为了保持一致，您还可以再次使用反斜杠字符。
just to be consistent, you can also use that backslash character again.
我们刚才看到了。
We saw the /n a moment ago.
这意味着我们不希望字面 n 出现在输出中,
And that meant we don't want a literal n to be in the output,
我们想要一条新的生产线。
we wanted a new line.
所以反斜杠实际上代表了所谓的转义字符。
So the backslash actually represents what's called an escape character.
逃脱角色是一个你不能
An escape character is one that you can't just
在键盘上必须打一次字。
type necessarily once on your keyboard.
您需要使用多个字符来表示它。
You need to express it with multiple characters.
所以我可以在这些内双引号前面加上反斜杠
So I can actually put backslashes in front of these inner double quotes
这样计算机就会意识到，哦，等一下,
so that the computer realizes, Oh wait a minute,
那些不是完成或开始思考的引号，而是字面上的引号。
those aren't quotes that finish or start the thought, they're literal quotes.
现在让我回到我的终端窗口，运行 Python of Hello.py，Enter。
So now let me go back to my terminal window, run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
现在它也起作用了。
And now it's working as well.
所以逃逸是一种普遍的技术，它也允许我们这样做。
So escaping is a general technique that allows us to do that too.
如果可以的话，让我们回顾一下这些例子
And if I may, let me rewind now on these examples
然后回到我们停止的地方，用我的代码,
and go back to where we left off with my code,
我只是想撤销这一切，因为我想回到正题上来
I'm just undoing all of that, because I want to get back to the point
最终确定了解决这个问题的最终方法。
ultimately of specifying now a final way of solving this problem.
看来我们还有别的办法
Well, it turns out that we have yet another way
我们可以解决这个问题，这可能是最常做的
we can solve this problem, which is perhaps the most frequently done
现在，或者至少是我们相亲时最优雅的时候
now or at least the most elegant when it comes to setting us up
字符串的使用时间越来越长。
for longer and longer uses of strings.
您可以使用 Python 的一个相对较新的特性来实现这一点。
You can use a relatively new feature of Python that allows you to do this.
你可以直接输入字符串中变量的名字,
You can literally put, not the name of the variable like that in your string,
因为我们已经知道这是错的，对吧？
because we already saw this is wrong, right?
如果您这样做，您将逐字地看到 Hello，逗号，名称。
If you do this, you will literally see Hello, comma, name.
但如果我这么做呢？
But what if I do this?
如果我在变量的名称周围放大括号或者大括号会怎么样？
What if I put curly braces or curly brackets around the variable's name?
注意 VS 代码实际上正在非常微妙地改变它的颜色。
Notice VS Code is actually very subtly changing the color of it.
所以 VS 代码知道这里发生了一些有趣的事。
So VS Code knows something interesting is going on here.
让我运行这个程序，但我还没有完成 Python 的 Hello.py，Enter。
Let me run this program, but I'm not done yet Python of Hello.py, Enter.
D-A-V-I-D，回车。
D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
好吧，显然不是我想要的但我得告诉巨蟒
OK, obviously not what I want, but I need to tell Python
这是一个特殊的字符串。
that this is a special string.
我们称之为格式字符串或者 F 字符串,
This is what we're going to call a format string or an F string,
在过去的几年里 Python 的一个相对较新的特性
a relatively new feature of Python in the past few years
它告诉 Python 以一种特殊的方式格式化字符串中的内容。
that tells Python to actually format stuff in the string in a special way.
这个符号有点奇怪,
And the symbol via what you do this is a little weird,
但这是世界的选择。
but this is what the world chose.
如果你在字符串的开头放一个 F,
If you put an F at the beginning of the string,
就在第一个引号之前这是 Python 的线索,
right before the first quote mark, that's a clue to Python that, ooh,
这是一根特殊的弦。
this is a special string.
让我用一种特殊的方式为你格式化它。
Let me format this in a special way for you.
现在让我重新运行程序。
Let me now rerun the program.
Python Hello.py，Enter.
Python Hello.py, Enter.
D-A-V-I-D，回车。
D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
现在我们终于看到了目标
And now we see the goal this whole time--
你好，大卫。
Hello, David.
我们不用这种方式开始因为我觉得如果我们用第一种方式,
We don't start with this way, because I think if we did this the first way,
你会想，我们为什么要这么做？
you'd be like, why are we doing this?
这些魔法符号是什么？
What are all these magical symbols?
但这只是解决同样问题的另一种方法。
But this is just yet another way to solve the same problem.
但我建议我们现在就考虑
But let me propose that we consider now yet
其他我们可以用弦来做的事情。
other things we can do with strings.
事实证明，即使我们做了一些相对简单的操作
And it turns out that even as we've been doing some relatively simple operations
在这里，我们一直相信用户会合作
here, we've generally been trusting that the user is going to cooperate
也就是说他们会输入我们想要他们输入的内容
and that is to say that they're going to actually type in what we want them
打字。
to type.
虽然他们输入了字符串，但这并不意味着
Now just because they type a string, though, doesn't mean
会是我们想要的样子。
it's going to look the way we want.
你和我，说实话，就像人类一样
You and I, honestly, as humans are actually
在网站和应用程序上，有意外撞击的习惯
in the habit-- on websites and apps-- of like accidentally hitting
空格键很多，无论是在我们的输入的开始
the spacebar a lot, either at the beginning of our input
或者在最后，也许是因为空格键太大了。
or at the end, maybe because the space bar tends to be so big.
意外空格很常见
It's pretty common to get accidental spaces
在一些用户输入之前或之后。
before or after some users' input.
你和我绝对是习惯了不用大写字母
You and I are definitely in the habit of not necessarily capitalizing words
就像我们应该做的那样。
like we should.
如果我们发短信的话，可能有点太快了
If we're sending text messages, we're probably being a little quick
把所有东西都用小写字母发送出去,
and just sending everything in lowercase,
比如，如果这是你的风格，如果你的手机没有为你修好。
for instance, if that's your style, if your phone's not fixing it for you.
也许在一封正式的信中，你可以恰当地使用大写字母。
Maybe in a formal letter you would capitalize things properly.
但是你和我作为人类，我们不能被信任去用一种很好的方式打字
But you and I as humans, we can't really be trusted to type things in a nice way
当使用某个软件的时候,
necessarily when using some piece of software,
不管是应用程序还是网站还是别的什么。
be it an app or a website or something else.
但事实证明，弦自己就会出现
But it turns out that strings themselves come
有很多内置的功能。
with a lot of built-in functionality.
您可以在 Python 自己的文档中看到所有这些内容。
You can see all of that in Python's own documentation here.
我们一直在讨论的字符串数据类型
The string data type that we've been talking about
内置了很多功能
comes with a lot of functionality built in that
意味着我们可以操纵用户的输入来做更多的事情
means that we can manipulate the user's input to do more than just
加入其他东西，比如 Hello，我们可以把它清理干净
join it with something else like Hello, we can actually clean it up
或者重新格式化，希望看起来对我们更好一点。
or reformat it in a way that hopefully looks a little better for us.
让我们回到我的代码
So let me go back to my code here and let me just
演示如果用户不合作可能发生的情况。
demonstrate what might happen if a user doesn't cooperate.
如果我继续运行 Python of Hello.py，回车。
If I go ahead here and run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
让我多按几次空格键。
Let me just sloppily hit the spacebar a few too many times.
为什么？
Why?
我只是没注意。
I just wasn't paying attention.
现在我要输入我的名字 D-A-V-I-D 我不知道,
And now I'm going to type in my name D-A-V-I-D and, I don't know,
我又按了几次空格键。
I hit the spacebar a couple more times.
好像一团糟。
Like it's kind of a mess.
都是小写的。
It's all lowercase.
这看起来不一定语法正确。
That's not going to necessarily look grammatically right.
这里和这里都有空格。
It's got spaces here and here.
程序会准确地打印出来
The program is going to print exactly that
这看起来很糟糕，至少如果我们
and that looks really bad, at least if we're
优先考虑美学和语法。
prioritizing aesthetics and grammar.
为什么逗号后面有这么多空格？
Like, why are there so many spaces after the comma?
这不是一种欢迎用户的非常好的方式。
This is not a very nice way to greet your users.
但我们可以清理干净。
But we can clean this up.
结果是内置到字符串中，同样是这个数据类型，所以
It turns out that built into strings, which, again, is this data type, so
可以说，Python 中的这种类型的数据——
to speak, this type of data in Python--
就是对字符串做实际操作的能力。
is the ability to actually do things to that string.
让我这样做，我可以继续做这样的事情——
So let me do this, I can actually go ahead and do something like this--
Name = name.Strip.
name = name.strip.
这个有什么用？
And what does this do?
删除字符串中的空白。
Remove white space from string.
我这么说是什么意思？
And what do I mean by this?
好吧，在右手边，注意我已经
Well, on the right-hand side, notice I've
编写了名为 Name 的变量名。
written the variable name called Name.
然后我用一个句点或点，然后我
I've then used a period or a dot, and then I
看起来像是在做某种功能，对吧？
seem to be doing what's a function, right?
到目前为止，每当我们看到一个函数时，我们都会看到该函数的名称—— print
Any time we've seen a function thus far, we see the function's name-- print
或者输入，然后我们看到一个括号，然后另一个括号,
or input, then we see a parenthesis, then another parenthesis,
这就是我在这里看到的。
and that's exactly what I see here.
但是我使用这个函数的方式有点不同。
But I'm using this function a little differently.
从技术上讲，这个函数在上下文中称为方法。
Technically, this function is-- in this context-- called a method.
我这么说是什么意思？
And what do I mean by that?
如果 Name 是字符串，也就是。
Well, if Name is a string, a.k.a.
STR 事实证明，根据文件记载,
STR, well it turns out, according to the documentation,
在 Python 中有很多字符串附带的函数。
there's a lot of functions that come with strings in Python.
您可以通过使用
And you can access that functionality by using
一个字符串的名字，比如这里的字面名字，然后是句点，然后是名字
the name of a string like literally name here, then a period, then the name
函数的，然后是一个开括号和一个闭括号。
of the, function and then an open parenthesis and a closed parenthesis.
也许这些括号里有一些参数但在这个例子中,
Maybe some arguments inside of those parentheses, but in this case,
不需要任何争论。
it doesn't need any arguments.
我只想把左边的空间和左边的空间分开
I just want to strip the space from the left and the space
从用户输入的右边。
from the right of the user's input.
但这还不够。
But that's not enough.
我想记住我已经脱光了
I want to remember that I've stripped off
左边和右边的空白处,
that white space on the left and the right,
所以我要在这里再用一次等号。
so I'm going to use the equal sign again here.
请注意，和以前一样，这并不意味着平等,
And notice that just as before, this doesn't mean equality,
这意味着从右到左的作业。
this means assignment from right to left.
所以当这行代码—— name. Strip ——
So when this line of code here-- name.strip--
回到我身边，也就是。
returns to me, a.k.a.
返回值，它将返回相同的值
a return value, it will return the same thing
用户输入的，但左边没有更多的空白
that the user typed in, but with no more white space to the left
或白色[笑]到右边。
or to the white [CHUCKLES] to the right.
那么等号赋值就是
So then the equal sign assignment is going
从右向左复制该值,
to copy that value from the right to the left,
从而更新 name 变量内部的值。
thereby updating the value inside of my name variable.
所以你不仅可以给变量赋值,
So you can not only assign values to variables,
你完全可以改变变量的值
you can absolutely change the value of variables
通过使用赋值运算符等号,
by just using the assignment operator, the equal sign again,
一次又一次，它只是从右边复制
and again, and again, and it will just keep copying from right
留下新的值。
to left whatever the new value should be.
所以现在如果我重新运行这个程序，Python of Hello.py，Enter。
So now if I rerun this program, Python of Hello.py, Enter.
我有 D-A-V-I ——噢，我们再来一次。
I have D-A-V-I-- oop, let's do it again.
空间，空间，空间，空间 d-a-v-i-d 全小写，空间,
Space, space, space, space, space. d-a-v-i-d in all lowercase, space,
空间，回车。
space, Enter.
这样更好。
It's better.
它没有固定我的资本，所以我仍然
It hasn't fixed my capitalization, so I'm still
第一个 D 有点草率，但已经脱落了
being a little sloppy with the first D, But it has stripped off
所有那些额外的空间。
all of that extra space.
超级小细节，对吧？
Super minor detail, right?
好像这一切都不那么令人兴奋，但是
Like this isn't all that exciting, but it just
说明了只需要一行代码就可以完成的工作的力量。
speaks to the power of what you can do with just a single line of code.
我还能做什么？
Now what else can I do here?
我可以大写用户的输入。
Well I could capitalize the user's input.
让我试试这个。
Let me go ahead and try this.
事实证明，我也可以这么做，名字，大写。
It turns out that I could also do this-- name.capitalize.
所以让我继续，并大写用户的名称。
So let me go ahead and capitalize user's name.
再说一遍，我在发表评论
And again, I'm making comments and there's
没有一个正确的写评论的方法。
no one right way to write the comments.
我只是在这里使用一些简短的英语短语
I'm just using some short English phrases here
提醒自己在做什么。
to remind myself of what I'm doing.
这是怎么回事？
What's now going on here?
让我继续运行 Python of Hello.py，Enter。
Well let me go ahead and run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
空间，空间，空间，空间，空间 d-a-v-i-d，空间，空间，回车。
Space, space, space, space, space, d-a-v-i-d, space, space, Enter.
好的。
OK.
现在看起来更漂亮了，对吧？
Now it's looking prettier, right?
不管用户怎么输入他们的名字哪怕有一点马虎,
No matter how the user typed in their name, even a little sloppily,
我现在正在解决这个问题。
I'm now fixing that.
但我们试试别的办法。
But let's try something.
我有点好奇。
I'm getting a little curious here.
这个怎么样？
How about this?
空间，空间，空间，空间 d-a-v-i-d 空间 m-a-l-a-n
Space, space, space, space, space, d-a-v-i-d space m-a-l-a-n--
我现在用我的姓
I'll use my last name now--
进来。
Enter.
好吧，讽刺的是“大写”并不是我们想要的所有东西都大写。
OK, so ironically, "capitalize" is not really capitalizing everything we want.
这明显是在利用什么？
It's clearly capitalizing what?
只有第一个字母。
Just the very first letter.
事实证明，在 Python 中还有其他函数
So it turns out that, again, there's other functions in Python
都是有条件的。
that come with strings.
如果我们浏览这些文档滚动浏览这样的网址,
And if we poke around the documentation, scrolling through a URL like that,
我打赌我们会找到另一个解决方案，其中之一就是这个。
I bet we'll find another solution, one of which is actually this.
我们把这个改成标题吧。
Let's actually change this to title.
还有一个带字符串的函数
There's yet another function that comes with strings
称为“标题”，以标题为基础进行大写
called Title that do title-based capitalization, just
像一本书或一个人的名字，大写
like a book or a person's name, capitalizing
每个单词的首字母。
the first letter of each word.
这只是为我们做更多的工作。
And this is just going to do a little more work for us.
让我们继续运行这个程序。
So let's go ahead and run this.
顺便说一句，我现在有点累了
And as an aside, I'm kind of tired now at this point
一直在输入 Python，Python，Python。
of typing Python, Python, Python all the time.
事实证明，在使用这样的命令行界面时,
It turns out that when using a command line interface like this,
你实际上可以重新执行所有的旧命令。
you can actually go back through all of your old commands.
我刚才按了向上箭头。
What I just did a moment ago was I hit the up arrow.
这会立即回顾我所有命令的历史
That immediately goes back through my history of all of the commands
最好的打字机。
I've ever typed.
所以这只是我重复自己的一种更快的方式
So this is just a faster way now for me to repeat myself
而不是手动打字。
than typing everything manually.
让我继续按回车，空格，空格，空格，空格，空格,
Let me go ahead and hit Enter, space, space, space, space, space,
d-a-v-i-d m-a-l-a-n 空格，小写，回车。
d-a-v-i-d m-a-l-a-n space, space, all lowercase, Enter.
现在看起来好多了。
Now it's looking better.
现在我已经把事情都搞定了。
Now I've capitalized things and cleaned things up.
那我的原则呢？
But what about my code?
我现在有八行代码，其中四行
I've got like eight lines of code now, four of which
是注释，其中四个是实际的代码。
are comments, four of which are actual code.
我真的需要这么多吗？
Do I really need this much?
不一定。
Well, not necessarily.
看看我在 Python 中还能做些什么。
Watch what I can also do in Python.
让我不必分别将用户的名称大写。
Let me not bother capitalizing the user's name separately.
我这么说吧
Let me say this--
大写用户名。
and capitalize user's name.
我可以把这些功能连接起来。
I can chain these functions together.
我可以把 Title 添加到这个结尾。
I can add Title to the end of this.
现在是什么情况？
And now what's happening?
再说一遍，像这样的一行代码,
Well again, with a line of code like this,
你首先关注等号右边是什么,
you first focus on what's to the right of the equal sign,
然后我们到等号的左边。
then we'll get to the left of the equal sign.
等号右边是什么？
What's on the right of the equals sign?
这条线。
This line here.
这是什么意思？
Well what does this mean?
获取 name 变量的值，如 D-A-V-I-D 空间、 M-A-L-A-N。
Get the value of the name variable, like D-A-V-I-D space, M-A-L-A-N.
然后去掉左边和右边的空白。
Then strip off the white space on the left and the right.
将返回一个值。
That is going to return a value.
它将返回没有任何空白的 D-A-V-I-D 空间 M-A-L-A-N
It's going to return D-A-V-I-D space M-A-L-A-N without any white space
向左或向右。
to the left or right.
您希望如何处理这个返回值？
What do you want to do with that return value?
你想让 Python 把它命名为 case
You want Python to title case it, that is
仔细检查所生成字符串中的每个单词
go through every word in that resulting string
把第一个单词的第一个字母，第一个字母
and fix the first letter of the first word, the first letter
第二个单词，等等。
of the second word, and so forth.
然后，现在我们可以完成我们的想法了
And then-- now we can finish our thought--
把整个东西从右到左复制到同一个 name 变量中。
copy the whole thing from right to left into that same name variable.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
我可以更进一步。
I can take this even one step further.
如果我们想的话，为什么不直接开始呢。
Why don't we go ahead and do this if we want.
让我摆脱这一切，让我只做脱衣舞和标题
Let me get rid of all of that, and let me just do strip and title
都在第一行。
all on that first line.
现在我们已经从8行代码变成了4行。
And now we've gone from like eight lines of code to four.
更紧了。
It's a lot tighter.
干净多了。
It's a lot neater.
尽管理智的人可能不这么认为,
And even though reasonable people might disagree,
可以说它更好，因为它更容易阅读。
it's arguably better because it's just easier to read.
代码越少，出错的机会越少,
Fewer lines of code, fewer opportunities for mistakes,
这样我就可以继续解决下一个问题了。
it just allows me to move on with my next problem to solve.
好吧，我暂停一下看看这些方法有没有问题。
All right, let me pause here and see if there's any questions on these methods.
方法是一个内置于值类型中的函数,
A method is a function that's built in to a type of value,
就像这些功能一样。
like these functions are.
或者在 F 弦上，我们刚才看到了。
Or on F strings which we saw a moment ago.
观众: 是的，你好。
AUDIENCE: Yes, hi.
谢谢，大卫。
Thanks, David.
那么有没有办法去除空格之间的空格
So is there a way to remove the spaces between the spaces
我可能加进去的东西吗？
that I might have added?
大卫. 马兰: 简短的回答，不。
DAVID MALAN: Short answer, no.
如果您在同一个 URL 上阅读文档,
If you read the documentation at that same URL earlier,
你会看到条带从左右两边移开，但不会在两边之间。
you'll see that strip removes from the left and the right, but not in between.
事实上，还有另外两个字符串函数。
In fact, there's two other functions that come with strings.
一个叫 L 带，一个叫 R 带,
One is called L strip, the other is called R strip,
你可以选择其中一个。
that allow you to do one or the other.
如果我们想要去掉中间的空间,
If we want to start getting rid of space in the middle,
我们要做一个完全不同的魔术。
we're going to have to do a different trick altogether.
观众: 有多少函数可以像这个点条，点标题,
AUDIENCE: How many functions can be combine like this dot strip, dot title,
全部加起来。
all combined.
那么我们可以合并多少？
So how many we can combine?
大卫. 马兰: 是的，一个非常好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, a really good question.
技术上来说，你想要多少就有多少，但总有一天
Technically, as many as you want, but at some point
你的代码会看起来非常非常糟糕，对吧？
your code is going to start to look really, really bad, right?
因为代码行会变得非常非常长。
Because the line of code is going to get really, really long.
它最终可能会一次又一次地缠绕。
It's eventually going to maybe wrap around again and again.
所以在某种程度上，你会说，呃，呃，太多了。
So at some point, you just kind of say like, uh-uh, that's too many.
然后你开始像我一样把它分成几行。
And you start breaking it up into multiple lines like I did.
也许根据需要将值重新分配给变量。
Maybe reassigning the value to the variable as needed.
这其实是个好问题。
And this is actually a good question.
如果我能绕开你的问题，我是说，人们会怎么想？
If I can pivot, [INAUDIBLE] off your question, I mean, what do people think?
请大家先把手放下。
If we could go ahead and put everyone's hands down for a moment.
让我问问
Let me ask this--
就是我现在做这件事的方式，使用带、标题和输入
is the way I've done this now, with strip and title and input
都在同一条线上
all in the same line--
比我之前的方法更好吗？
better than my previous approach?
在缩放中，你可以使用“是”图标或“否”图标。
In Zoom you can use the Yes icon or the No icon.
如果你认为这个版本更好，说是。
If you think this version is better, say Yes.
例如，如果你认为以前的版本更好,
If you think this previous version was better, for instance,
这里我们所有的东西都爆炸了，说不。
this one here where we had everything broken out, say No.
然后我们马上就知道为什么了。
And then we'll see why in just a moment.
我之前提出，理性的人可以有不同意见
I proposed earlier that reasonable people can disagree
绝对是这样。
and that's absolutely the case.
不管怎样都不一定是最好的,
Doing it one way or the other isn't necessarily best,
至少如果你能证明的话。
at least if you can justify it.
让我们回到最近的版本。
Let me go back to the most recent version here.
好吧，我们看到很多人同意，很多人反对。
All right so we're seeing a lot of Yeses and a lot of Nos.
如果可以的话，我们为什么不去拜访一个赞成者呢。
Why don't we go ahead and call on one of the Yeses, if we could.
是的，为什么你认为这个代码的当前版本
Someone who's voting Yes, why do you think the current version of this code
是否真的比以前的较长版本的代码更好？
is indeed better than the previous longer version of the code?
观众: 我认为它更易读。
AUDIENCE: I think it's more readable.
我可以说，这是 name 变量。
So I can say, this is the name variable.
它获得一些输入，然后删除空格并给它一个标题。
It gets some input and then remove the space and give it a title.
就是这样。
And there you go.
你好，名字。
You have a hello, name.
大卫. 马兰: 是的，我认为这很合理。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, I think that's pretty reasonable.
它非常易读，至少如果你有这个习惯的话,
It's very readable, at least if you're in the habit,
就像你用英语一样，从左往右读。
as you are in English, of reading left to right.
结果就变得非常自然了。
It just kind of flows very naturally as a result.
队伍其实没那么长。
The lines is not really that long.
放在屏幕上很合适。
It's certainly fitting nicely onto the screen.
所以我认为这是一个很好的论点。
So I think that's a good argument.
不过，来个对位怎么样？
How about a counterpoint, though?
一个投反对票的人，如果我们能找到一个认为情况更糟的人。
Someone who voted No, if we could call on someone who thinks this is worse.
观众: 因为它根本不可读。
AUDIENCE: Because it's not readable at all.
好像排了很长的队。
It seems like it's a very long line.
所以我觉得还是分开比较好。
So I think it's better to separate.
是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
我觉得这也很有说服力，对吧？
I think that's persuasive too, right?
时间有点长了。
It's getting a little longer.
尽管我这里的句子——你叫什么名字——相对较短,
And even though my sentence here-- what's your name-- is relatively short,
你可以想象这会很快变得更糟
you could imagine that this could get even uglier quickly
如果我问用户一个更长的问题，那就是
if I were asking a longer question of the user, that's
会使这行代码更长，因此可读性更差。
going to make this line of code even longer and therefore less readable.
对我或我的同事来说，我称之为脱衣舞可能不那么明显
It might be less obvious to me or my colleagues that I am calling strip
或者我称之为头衔。
or that I am calling title.
这可能是个意想不到的惊喜。
It might be kind of an unexpected surprise.
所以我认为这也是合理的。
So I think that's reasonable too.
简而言之，这里没有正确的答案。
In short, there is no right answer here.
事实上，这也是提高编程能力的过程之一
And in fact, part of the process of getting better at programming
就是找到自己的风格，或者为一家公司工作
is getting your own sense of style or working for a company
在那里他们可能会规定哪种方式比另一种更好
where they might prescribe which way is better than the other
因为他们希望每个人都做同样的事情,
because they just want everyone doing the same thing,
即使理智的人可能不同意。
even though reasonable people might disagree.
但最终，只要你拥有
Ultimately though, so long as you have what's
一个很好的支持这个或那个的论点，就像最终,
a pretty good argument in favor of one way or the other, like ultimately,
这才是最重要的。
that's what's important.
如果你做这些事只是因为你不知道哪个更好,
If you're just doing things because you don't really know which one is better,
这可不妙。
that's not great.
但是当你开始获得意见的时候
But if and when you start to acquire opinions
如果你的老板，你的老师，你的同事，你的朋友,
and if your boss, if your teacher, if your colleague, your friend,
可以挑战你，说，等等，你为什么这样做呢？
can challenge you and say, wait, why did you do it like this?
他们可能不同意你的观点，但至少有个答案,
They might not agree with you, but at least have an answer,
一般来说，这应该足够有说服力。
and that should be sufficiently persuasive in general.
现在，字符串附带了一大堆其他方法
Now, strings come with a whole bunch of other methods
其中有一种叫做分裂，顾名思义,
as well, among which is one called split, which can, as the name suggests,
可以说，把一个字符串分成多个较小的子字符串。
split a string into multiple smaller substrings, so to speak.
例如，如果这里的人类有这样的习惯
For instance, if the human here is in the habit
输入他们的名字，然后是空格，然后是他们的姓,
of typing in their first name, then a space, and then their last name,
你只想用名字迎接他们,
and you want to go ahead and greet them only by first name,
我们可以利用这个空间
well we could actually leverage that single space
在名字和姓之间切分字符串
between the first name and last name and split that string
分成两个更小的子弦。
into two smaller substrings.
我们要怎么做？
How can we do this?
好吧，让我继续在这些线之间
Well, let me go ahead and in between these lines
主动评论说我们要拆分用户的
proactively comment that we're about to split user's
名字变成姓和名。
name into first name and last name.
然后我们继续，获取名称变量，它当前包含
And then let's go ahead and take that name variable, which currently contains
比如大卫，太空，马兰,
something like, presumably, David, space, Malan,
让我继续调用 Split 并将其作为参数传入
and let me go ahead and call split and pass in as the argument
分割出一个单独的空白，从而表明我确实
to split a single white space, thereby indicating that I indeed
想要在这个角色上分裂
want to split on that character
现在，在理想情况下，Split 将返回一个值序列
Now it turns out split is going to return a sequence of values, ideally
先是名，然后是姓。
a first name and then a last name.
实际上，在 Python 中，我们可以同时赋这两个值
And we can actually, in Python, assign both of those values
从这个序列到某些变量。
from that sequence at once to some variables.
例如，第一个逗号最后一个等于
For instance, first comma last equals, and that's
将会产生从右到左的影响
going to have the effect from right to left
将第一个这样的值放入第一个变量，第二个这样的值
of putting the first such value in the first variable, the second such value
在第二个变量中。
in the second variable.
所以现在在我的最后一行代码中，我可以进去打个招呼
So now on my last line of code, I can go in and say hello
不是全名，比如大卫 · 马兰,
not to the full name, something like David Malan,
我可以先打个招呼。
I can just say Hello, first.
好了，清空我的终端窗口运行 Python 的 Hello.py
All right, let's go ahead and clear my terminal window, run Python of Hello.py
然后按回车键。
and hit Enter.
这次我不会再为任何前导空白而烦恼了，但是让我继续
I won't bother with any leading white space this time, but let me go ahead
然后输入 David Space Malan 像往常一样祈祷，你好,
and type in David space Malan, and crossing my fingers as usual, Hello,
大卫就是我们现在看到的。
David is what we now see.
好了，我们已经看到了太多，太多的例子
All right, so we've seen so much, so many examples thus far involving
字符串，但是程序和编程语言当然可以
strings, but certainly programs and programming languages can
也可以处理其他类型的数据。
manipulate other types of data as well.
让我们继续，然后转换到另一种非常常见的数据类型
Let's go ahead and transition then to another very common type of data
在 Python 中，更一般地说，在编程中，即
in Python, in programming more generally, namely
整数，在 Python 中又称为 INT ——
integers, otherwise known in Python as INT--
正如 STR，S-T-R 是字符串的缩写，Python 中的 INT 也是如此
I-N-T. So just as STR, S-T-R is short for string, so is INT in Python
整数的缩写。
short for integer.
整数是什么？
Well, what's an integer?
就像数学中的负2一样,
Well just like in math it's a number like negative 2,
负1,0,1,2，一直到负无穷大
negative 1, 0, 1, 2, and all the way toward negative infinity, all
走向正无穷大的道路。
the way toward positive infinity.
但是整数中没有小数点。
But there's no decimal point in an integer.
它只是一个负2，负1,0,1，和2的数字。
It's just a number like negative 2, negative 1, 0, 1, and 2 onward.
那是智力。
That's an INT.
当然，在数学的世界里，我们使用了很多符号。
Of course, in the world of mathematics, there's lots of symbols that we use.
我们以前也见过 + ，尽管我们用它来做不同的用途。
And we've seen + before, although we used it for a different purpose.
但是 Python 支持这些符号以及更多的东西。
But Python supports these symbols and more.
Python 允许你把数字相加 + ,
And Python allows you to add numbers together +,
减数，乘数，除数。
subtract numbers, multiply numbers, divide numbers.
这里唯一一个看起来有点陌生或者不熟悉的人
And the only one here that might look a little strange to people or unfamiliar
是这个百分比符号，但在这个上下文中它并不意味着百分比。
is this percent sign, but it doesn't mean percent in this context.
如果在 Python 程序中使用单个百分号,
If you use a single percent sign in a Python program,
这就是所谓的模运算符,
that's actually the so-called modulo operator,
允许你在除数后求余数的运算符
the operator that allows you to take the remainder after dividing
一个号码接着一个号码。
one number by another.
我们很快就会看到这样的例子，但是前四个
So we'll see examples of that before long, but the first four of these
可能非常非常熟悉。
are perhaps quite, quite familiar.
事实证明，在 Python 中，你不一定——
Well it turns out that in Python you cannot necessarily--
您不必一直在 Hello.py 这样的文件中编写代码
you don't necessarily have to keep writing code in a file like Hello.py
然后在终端窗口中运行它。
and then running it in a terminal window.
很多人喜欢 Python 的一个特性
One of the features that many people like about Python
它支持这种所谓的交互模式。
is that it supports this so-called interactive mode.
就像您可以开始编写 Python 代码并立即执行
Like you can start writing Python code and immediately execute
每一行都是互动的，尤其是
each of those lines interactively, especially
如果您不在乎保存所有的代码行。
if you don't care about saving all of your lines of code.
您只需要执行代码并返回一些答案。
You just want to execute code and get back some answers.
例如，让我回到这里的 VS Code 并关闭 Hello.py
So for instance, let me go back to VS Code here and let me close Hello.py
让我点击终端窗口中的这个小三角形
and let me click on the little triangle over here in my terminal window just
让它变得更大只是暂时的。
to make it much bigger just temporarily for a moment.
所以我现在不创建任何.py 文件，我只是要自己运行 Python
So I'm not creating any .py file now, I'm just going to run Python by itself
在我的提示下。
at my prompt.
当我这样做的时候，你会看到一些神秘的输出
And you'll see when I do this, I get some cryptic looking output
以及程序上次更新的日期和时间等等。
and the date and time at which the program was last updated, and so forth.
但我最终得到了三个这样的三重括号。
But I ultimately get three triple brackets like this.
是 Python 的交互模式。
Is the interactive mode for Python.
所以我在运行 Python 解释器，每当我键入一行代码时
So I'm running the Python interpreter and any time I type a line of code
在解释器中，它会立即执行。
in the interpreter, it's going to execute it immediately.
我不需要一次又一次地运行 Python。
I don't have to keep running Python again and again.
就好像在人类世界里，如果你
It's as though in the human world, if you
站在一个会说其他语言的人类旁边,
were standing next to a human who speaks some other language,
你只是和他们来回交谈,
and you're just having a conversation with them back and forth,
一切都在发生，翻译，马上。
it's all happening-- the translation-- immediately.
那么在交互模式下我可以做什么呢？
So what might I do in interactive mode?
我可以做1 + 1，回车。
Well I could do something like 1 + 1, Enter.
那其实是暗号，好吗？
That's actually code, all right?
你可能不认为它是代码，但如果一点算术和你
You might not think of it as code, but if a bit of arithmetic and you
知道数字，你知道 + ，这是有效的 Python 代码。
know numbers, and you know +, that's valid Python code.
你可以把 Python 当作一个很棒的计算器。
And you can use Python really as a fancy calculator.
但是我也可以做其他的事情。
But I could do other things too.
如果我想打印给自己，你好，世界,
If I want to print to myself Hello, world,
我也可以把那行代码打印出来
I can also print out that line of code there too--
你好，世界。
Hello, world.
所以它是互动的，在某种意义上
So it's interactive in the sense that the moment
你只要执行一行代码，砰，你就能看到结果。
you execute a line of code, boom, you see the result.
我们通常不会这么做，因为至少当
We're generally not going to do that because at least when
教语言时，我们倾向于渐进地做事情
teaching the language, we tend to want to do things incrementally
我们希望你能看到我们从哪里来。
and we want you to be able to see where it is we came from.
我们希望能够一次又一次地尝试，特别是
And we want to be able to try things again and again, especially
如果我们犯了错。
if we make mistakes.
但要知道这确实是 Python 的一个特性,
But know that this is indeed a feature of Python,
这个所谓的交互模式。
this so-called interactive mode.
但现在让我们关注一下，不仅仅是互动,
But let's focus for a moment now, not just on that interactivity,
但实际上巨蟒
but really on the fact that Python apparently
支持整数和数学以及一些基本运算。
supports integers and mathematics and some of those basic operations.
看看我们能不能做出我们自己的小计算器。
And let's see if we can't make maybe our own little calculator.
让我再打开 VS 代码,
So let me go ahead and open up VS Code again,
我要缩小我的终端窗口,
and I'm going to shrink down my terminal window,
我将创建一个名为 Calculator.py 的新文件。
and I'm going to create a new file called Calculator.py.
为了进行回忆，我可以在这里输入代码,
So to do that recall, I can type Code down here,
以及要创建的文件的名称: . py，Enter。
and the name of the file I want to create, .py, Enter.
这给了我一个新的账单。
That gives me a new tab up top.
我已经关闭了 Hello.py。
So I have already closed Hello.py.
我现在在 Calculator.py。
I'm now in Calculator.py.
让我们做一个简单的计算器，为我做一些加法。
And let's just make a simple calculator that does some addition for me.
但是我要在一个文件中进行，这样我们就可以对这个进行迭代
But I'm going to do it in a file so that we can iterate on this
随着时间的推移，不管是好是坏，都要做出改变。
and make changes for better or for worse over time.
让我先声明几个变量。
Let me go ahead and first declare a couple of variables.
我要用数学方法调用我的第一个变量 x,
I'm going to do the mathematical thing of calling my first variable x,
第二个变量 y，然后我给自己
my second variable y, and then I'm going to give myself
第三个变量 z = x + y。
a third variable z = x + y.
然后打印出 z。
And then I'm going to go ahead and print out z.
现在这个节目，诚然不是很精彩或有趣,
Now this program, admittedly not very exciting or interesting,
事实上，比起在屏幕上打印东西来说，这有点没意思
in fact, it's a little less interesting than printing stuff on the screen
就像以前用弦乐器一样，但我们会在此基础上再进一步
like before with strings, but we'll build on this
看看 Python 中还有哪些其他特性是我们可以利用的。
and see what other features exist in Python that we can leverage.
所以希望，如果 Python 和我一样懂数学,
So hopefully, if Python knows it's math as well as I do,
当我运行 Python of Calculator.py 时，我希望看到1 + 2
when I run Python of Calculator.py, I should see hopefully that 1 + 2
= 确实3。
= indeed 3.
好吧，没那么惊讶，也没那么有趣。
All right, so not that surprising and not that interesting.
老实说，这不是最有用的程序
And honestly this isn't the most useful program
因为它总是要计算1 + 2 = 3。
because it's always going to calculate 1 + 2 = 3.
让我们至少让这个节目，比如说，更加互动一点，好吗？
Let's at least make this program, say, a little more interactive, right?
从前面的例子中，我们已经知道如何从用户那里获得输入。
We already know from previous examples how we can get input from the user.
让我们回到输入函数。
Let's bring back that input function.
让我们这样做，让我现在继续，在我的代码的顶部,
And let's do this, let me go ahead now and at the top of my code,
我们把 x 改成不是数字1,
let's change x to not be the number 1 always,
让我们把它改成无论什么回报
let's change it to be whatever the return
值是要求用户输入 x。
value is of asking the user for x.
在这里，我可以使用任何我想要的英语或人类语言。
And I can use any English or human language I want here.
我会说，x 是什么？
I'm going to say, what's x?
就像我之前问的，你叫什么名字？
Just like I asked before, what's your name?
我也会为你做同样的事。
And I'm going to do the same thing for y.
我将再次使用 Input，但是这次将问题改为,
I'm going to use Input again, but this time change the question to be,
y 是什么？
what's y?
好了，现在，我想把剩下的代码留下
All right, at this point, I think I'm going to leave the rest of the code
一样。
the same.
Z = x + y，然后打印 z，不过好的方面是
Z = x + y And then print z but what's nice
现在我觉得我有一个很好的交互式计算器。
now is that I think I have a nice interactive calculator.
现在它不会一直做1 + 2了。
Right, now it's not going to do 1 + 2 all the time.
它将执行用户输入的任何操作 + 用户输入的任何操作。
It's going to do whatever the user types + whatever the user types.
我们试试这个。
So let's try this.
让我继续运行这个程序。
Let me go ahead and run that program.
好了，开始吧。
All right, let's do it.
1等于 x，2等于 y，当然，大家都同意，1
1 is going to be x, 2 is going to be y, and of course, everyone in agreement, 1
+ 2 = thr ——
+ 2 = thr--
嗯。
huh.
发生什么事了？
What's going on there?
要么是你的数学课误导了你，要么是我误导了你。
Either your math class misled you or I have misled you.
我们为什么不叫人来看看你呢
Why don't we call on someone here to see if you
不能帮助我们推理出漏洞是什么，错误是什么？
can't help us reason through what the bug is, what's the mistake?
Anjali 如果我没说错的话。
Anjali, if I'm saying it right.
听众: 我认为问题在于它连接字符串是因为
AUDIENCE: I think the issue is that it's concatenating strings because you
使用 + 运算符而不是添加。
use the + operator instead of adding.
完美。
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
完美的直觉。
So perfect intuition.
我们已经看到 + 在字符串上下文中的用法有些不同
We've seen that + is used a little differently in the context of strings
因为它连接就是连接两个字符串,
because it concatenates, that is, it joins the two strings,
看起来确实是这样,
and that seems to Indeed be what's happening here,
即使用户输入了一个数字。
even though the user typed a number.
但有趣的是
But the interesting thing here is that, when
你得到用户输入，因为他们在他们的 Mac 上使用键盘
you get user input, because they're using a keyboard on their Mac
或者电脑，或者他们的手机，它永远都是短信。
or PC or their phone, it is always going to be text.
看起来像个数字，但默认情况下,
It might look like a number, but by default,
从键盘发出的声音就像字符串
it's coming from the keyboard as a string--
也就是说，作为文本。
that is, as text.
所以，如果我们最终
And so, how do we go about resolving this if ultimately we
不想把这些输入当作字符串,
don't want to treat those inputs as strings,
我们要把它们当作实际的数字？
we want to treat them as actual numbers?
我们需要另一个函数，它是用 Python 写的
Well we need another function and it turns out in Python
有时候你可以把一种数据转换成另一种数据,
that you can convert sometimes from one type of data to another type of data,
例如，通过这样做，从字符串到 INT。
for instance, from string to INT by doing something like this.
让我回到我的代码，让我改变
Let me go back into my code and let me change
然后把它加到 y 中，变成 x 的整数形式
x before adding it to y to be whatever the integer version of x
是，+ 不管 y 的整数形式是什么。
is, + whatever the integer version of y is.
INT 不仅是 Python 中的一种数据类型,
So it turns out that INT is not only a type of data in Python,
它也是一个函数，一个函数
it's also a function, and it's a function
如果你传入一个输入，比如字符串,
that if you pass in an input, like a string,
只要字符串看起来像1或者2,
so long as that string looks like a number like 1 or like 2,
它会把它转换成一个实际的数，这样你就可以进行数学计算了
it will convert it to an actual number that you can perform mathematics
穿上。
on instead.
所以如果我现在回到我的终端窗口并运行 Python ——
So if I now go back to my terminal window and run Python--
我再教你一招。
and let me show you another trick.
“计算器”这个词有点长。
"Calculator" is kind of a long word.
打字有点乏味。
It's a little tedious to type.
请注意我可以在终端窗口的命令行中做什么
Notice what I can do in my terminal window, in a command line
一般界面。
interface in general.
如果我开始为计算器输入 C-A-L，我实际上可以
If I start typing C-A-L for calculator, I can actually
点击 Tab 来完成我的想法。
hit Tab to finish my thought.
所以在这样的终端窗口中自动完成是可能的。
So auto-complete is possible in a terminal window like this.
输入第一个字母或者几个字母然后，砰，用 Tab 键,
Type the first letter or few letters and then, boom, with Tab,
它会帮你完成你的思考。
it'll finish your thought for you.
或者你可以回到你的过去就像我对上下箭头乐队那样。
Or you can go back in your history like I did with the Up and Down Arrows.
让我来执行吧。
Let me go ahead and execute this.
X 是什么？
What's x?
1.
X 是什么？
What's x?
2.
好了。
And there we go.
现在我们有了一个通用计算器
Now we have a general purpose calculator that's going to support
不仅仅是1和2的加法，而是现在任意2的加法
not just the addition of 1 and 2, but now any two
用户键入的整数。
integers that the user types.
现在让我来改进一下，好吗？
And let me now improve this, right?
我们已经看到了如何改进代码
We've seen how we can make improvements to code
我不知道是否会变得更好,
and I don't know if it's going to necessarily be better,
但我们试试这个。
but let's try this.
我真的需要 z 变量吗？
Do I really need the z variable?
值得注意的是，我正在创建一个名为 z 的变量,
It's worth noting that I'm creating a variable called z,
然后立即在下一行代码中使用它。
and then I'm immediately using it on the next line of code.
现在这不是那么引人注目，因为如果你创建一个变量
Now that's not that compelling, because if you're creating a variable
然后立即使用它，但再也不会使用它,
and then immediately using it, but never again using it,
你真的需要花时间来介绍另一个符号吗
did you really need to take the time to introduce another symbol
和另一个变量，只是为了使用它一次和只有一次？
and another variable just to use it once and only once?
也许不是。
Well, maybe not.
也许我们真的不需要这样的 z。
Maybe we don't really need z in this way.
也许我应该去做这样的事情。
Maybe I should go and do something like this.
也许我应该把 Z 处理掉。
Maybe I should get rid of z here.
也许我应该把这个改成 INT，改
Maybe I should change this to be INT up here, change
这是 INT 在这里，做一些非常有趣的事情。
this to be INT up here, doing something that's pretty interesting now.
尽管这是一种新的语法，但请注意
Even though it's a bit of new syntax, notice that you
可以说，可以嵌套功能。
can nest functions, so to speak.
您可以放置一个函数调用，它是一个函数的使用
You can put one function call that is the use of a function
内部使用另一个函数，以便返回
inside of the use of another function so that the return
内部函数的值成为
value of the inner function becomes the argument to
或外部函数的输入。
or the input to the outer function.
就像数学一样，如果你有括号，括号，括号,
Just like in math, if you have parentheses, parentheses, parentheses,
你的老师可能教过你要集中注意力
your teacher probably taught you to focus
最里面的括号里面是什么
on what's inside the innermost parentheses first
然后自己想办法出去。
and then work your way out.
编程也是一样。
Same thing with programming.
这就是巨蟒要做的。
That's what's Python is going to do.
首先要看括号里面是什么,
It's going to look at what's inside of the parentheses first,
它会得到答案，然后
it's going to get the answer, and then it's
将返回值传递给最外面的函数。
going to pass the return value to the outermost function.
所以现在在第1行发生的是首先调用 input 函数,
So what happens on line 1 now is that the input function gets called first,
那么结果就是，引号1
then the result of that, quote unquote one
成为 INT 函数的输入，第2行也是如此。
becomes the input to the INT function, and same on line 2.
Y 的输出成为这个 INT 函数的输入。
The output of what's y becomes the input to this INT function.
现在没有僵尸了。
And now there is no z.
我可以打印 x + y。
I could just do print x + y.
因为我花时间转换了每一个字符串
And because I've taken the time to convert each of those strings
变成一个整数，我想我们可以了。
to an integer, I think we're OK.
让我试试这个，Python 的 Calculator.py，Enter。
So let me try this, Python of Calculator.py, Enter.
1和2我们还是得到了3。
1 and 2, and we're still getting 3.
不是12，也不是12,1,2，我们确实得到了3。
Not 12, or not 12, 1,2, we're indeed getting 3.
我们还去掉了变量
And we've additionally gotten rid of the variable
因为我们似乎不一定需要它,
because we didn't necessarily need it, it seems,
尤其是只用一次。
especially if only using it once.
这里也是，让我把大家的手放下来一会儿
Well here too, let me put everyone's hands down for just a moment
让我像以前一样问你
and let me ask as before--
这个版本现在使用 INT 来调用输入,
this version now which uses INT around the invocations of input,
并且没有使用 z，这是否比以前的版本更好？
and does not use z, is this better than the previous version?
如果你想投赞成票，请便。
If you want to vote Yes, go ahead.
或者如果你喜欢老办法，投反对票。
Or if you prefer the old way, vote No.
用老办法，我们投票的时候，我会撤销这一切，而不是像这样。
The old way, I'll undo all of this as we vote, instead looked like this.
好了，让我们回到最新的版本。
All right, and let me go back to now the newest version.
让我们来掌声鼓励
Let's take a hand of the Yeses, someone who
认为这个最新版本更好。
thinks this latest version is better.
观众: 我认为这种方式更好，因为它可以让我们立即看到
AUDIENCE: I think this way is better because it allows us to immediately see
整数的 x 和 y 变量是什么
what the x and y variables are with integers
所以我们知道从他们身上能得到什么。
and so we know what to expect from them.
而且打印参数更直观。
And also the print argument is more intuitive.
我们在代码中避免了太多的混乱。
We avoid too much clutter in the code.
大卫. 马兰: 我认为这些都是很好的理由。
DAVID MALAN: I think those are all good reasons.
简洁明了。
It's nice and succinct.
代码行不是很长。
The lines of code are not very long.
我不需要知道 z 是什么，因为它不存在。
I don't need to know what z is because it doesn't exist.
只能看到 x + y。
It just sees print x + y.
我喜欢。
I like that.
但是有人更喜欢我们曾经拥有 Z 的老方式
But someone who prefers the older way where we did have z
我们更明确地将单个变量传递给 INT 函数。
and we more explicitly passed individual variables to the INT function.
观众: 是的，嗨。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, hi.
我觉得早期的版本更好，因为..
I think that the earlier version is better because when--
如果用户输入的不是,
I mean, if user input something else other than,
比如说，我的意思是，比如说，他们输入1和2，比如,
let's say, I mean, let's say, they type 1 and 2, like,
所以调试起来更容易。
so it will be easier to debug.
大卫. 马兰: 这个版本还是——这个版本还是旧版本？
DAVID MALAN: This version or-- this version here or the old version?
观众: 老版本。
AUDIENCE: The old version.
大卫. 马兰: 好吧，这很公平。
DAVID MALAN: OK, that's fair.
事实上，我今天非常小心，尽我所能，不要搞砸了。
And in fact, I'm being very careful today, as best I can, not to mess up.
到目前为止，我只在期待整数时输入了整数。
I have thus far only inputted integers when I'm expecting integers.
而且拉乌尔实际上是在指着什么东西
And Raoul's actually pointing to something
我们将在接下来的几周内讨论，我们实际上如何处理错误？
we'll come back to in the coming weeks, how do we actually handle errors?
如果用户没有输入数字1或者数字2或者数字
What if the user doesn't type in the number 1 or the number 2, or a number
完全没有？
at all?
如果他们输入一个单词，比如 cat，C-A-T？
What if they type in a word like cat, C-A-T?
那不是一个数字，我打赌我不能把它转换成一个整数。
That's not a number, and I bet I can't convert it to an integer.
但是今天，我不会关注这个。
But for today, I'm not going to focus on that.
我只希望用户能合作。
I'm just going to hope that the user cooperates.
但事实并非如此。
But that's not going to be the case.
因此，也许有一种方法可以让我们取得更大的成功
And so perhaps one way would set us up for more success
当涉及到处理这些错误时。
when it comes to handling those errors.
就今天来说，哪个更好？
Now for today's purposes, which is better?
我两个都喜欢。
Eh, I mean, I like both.
我认为你们两个在那里也提出了非常有效的论点,
And I think both of you made very valid arguments in there too,
只要你有一个合理的理由。
so long as you have a justification that feels pretty reasonable.
这才是最重要的。
I mean, that's what ultimately matters.
但是，再一次获得了一种权衡的感觉。
But acquiring, again, a sense of the trade-offs here.
这样好点吗？
Well, is this way better?
如果是这样，为什么或为什么不呢？
If so, why or why not?
我只是想知道这些取舍是什么。
Just understanding what those trade-offs are.
但是一般来说，优先考虑可读性是一件非常好的事情。
But generally speaking, prioritizing readability is a very good thing.
使您的代码对其他人可读是一件非常好的事情
Making your code readable for someone else is a very good thing
对你也有好处这样你第二天早上醒来时,
and very good for you too so that when you wake up the next morning,
或者你下周再来，或者明年再来,
or you come back the next week, or the next year,
你也可以阅读自己的代码而不必浪费
you too can read your own code without having to waste
花时间回忆你的所作所为。
time trying to remember what you did.
简单性也是一件好事——保持代码简单。
And simplicity tends to be a good thing too-- keeping your code simple.
随着你对编程越来越熟悉,
So as you get more comfortable with programming,
您可能会试图将整个程序组合成一个长行。
you might be tempted to try to combine an entire program into one long line.
例如，让我这样做。
For instance, let me do just that.
从技术上讲，我们并不需要变量中的 x。
Technically speaking, we don't really need x in a variable.
在变量中我们不需要 y。
We don't really need y in a variable.
我们也可以这样
We could also do this--
我可以把 x 和 y 一起去掉。
I could just get rid of x and y altogether.
我现在可以消除它，使它只是一行代码。
I could then now eliminate that and make it just one line of code.
好吧，从某种意义上说，你可能倾向于认为，哇,
OK, so on some sense, you might be inclined to think, wow,
真不错。
that's really nice.
你只用了一行简单的代码。
You made it one simple line of code.
我觉得事情没那么简单。
I would argue this actually isn't that simple.
现在我觉得我已经开始筑巢了。
Now I think I'm starting to nest too many things.
我必须考虑打印、 INT 和输入。
I have to think about print and INT and input.
然后我要注意，我打开了两个括号,
I then have to notice that, OK, I've opened two parentheses,
我已经关了两家了。
I've closed two of them.
有个 + 。
There's a +.
你让我想太多了，每次你让我想,
You're making me think too much and any time you make me think,
你在浪费时间。
you're wasting time.
任何时候像这样复杂化代码的外观,
And any time you complicate the look of the code like this,
你只会增加出错的可能性
you're just going to increase the probability of mistakes
以及代码中的战术错误或逻辑错误。
and tactical mistakes or logical errors in your code.
所以如果我们做了那么多事这是唯一一件我会争辩的事,
So if all the things we've done, this is the only one that I would argue,
是的，这是一条线，它很好，紧凑。
yes, it's one line and it's nice and compact.
只是读起来不够清楚。
It's just not readable enough.
我会避免这样做，特别是因为其中两个函数
I would shy away from doing this, especially since two of those function
调用从用户那里获得输入。
calls are getting input from the user.
但在那里，理智的人可能不同意,
But there too, reasonable people might disagree,
但有时候你应该有这种发自内心的反应
but that's the kind of visceral reaction you should have sometimes when
代码开始变得有点太复杂，有点太聪明,
code starts getting a little too complicated, a little too clever,
也许是为了它自己好。
perhaps, for its own good.
好吧，我们可以访问的不仅仅是整数。
All right, well it's not just integers we have access to.
让我提议我们在这里从整数转换到另一种数据类型,
Let me propose that we transition from integers to one more data type here,
也就是花车。
namely a float.
同样，字符串是一个文本序列。
So again, a string is a sequence of text.
INT 是一个类似负1、0和1的整数。
An INT is an integer like negative 1, 0 and 1.
浮点数是一个带有小数点的数字，正确地称为浮点数
A float is a number with a decimal point, properly called a floating point
价值。
value.
你可以认为浮点是
And you can think of the floating point as being
小数可能在这里，也可能在这里有一些数字
the decimal that might be over here or over here with some number of digits
向左或向右。
to the left or the right.
从数学上讲，它是一个实数，一个有小数点的数。
Mathematically, it's a real number, a number that has a decimal point in it.
这是 Python 支持的第三种类型的数据。
So that's a third type of data that Python supports.
现在我们的计算器有点天真
Right now our calculator is somewhat naively
假设用户只输入整数,
assuming that the user is only going to type in integers,
但是如果我也想支持浮点值,
but if I want to support floating point values too,
我想我可以稍微调整一下。
I think I can just make a couple of tweaks.
所以我要回到 VS 代码这里。
So I'm going to go back to VS Code here.
而不是仅仅将用户的输入 x 和 y 转换为
And instead of just converting the user's input x and y to
第一行和第二行的整数，让我们做一个简单的更改。
integers on line 1 and 2, let's just make a simple change.
让我们把它转换成第一行的浮点数
Let's actually convert it to a float on the first line
第二行有一个浮子。
and a float on the second line here.
现在我想，如果我到终端窗口运行 Python 的 Calculator.py,
Now I think, if I go down to my terminal window and run Python of Calculator.py,
让我们输入一个带小数点的数字，比如1.2
let's type in a number like 1.2 with a decimal point
3.4加上小数点，就是这样。
and 3.4 with a decimal point, and there we go.
最终答案是4.6。
We have 4.6 as the final answer.
所以如果我之前只期待整数，那么这个方法就不会成功
So that wouldn't have worked before if I was only expecting integers
但是现在我期望的是浮点值
from the user, but now that I'm expecting floating point values
并适应它，我现在实际上也可以做浮点运算了。
and accommodating it, I can actually now do floating point arithmetic as well.
但假设我真的不想要最终的答案
But suppose that I don't really want the final answer
像4.6这样的浮点值。
to be a floating point value like 4.6.
如果我们四舍五入到最接近的整数，我会很高兴。
I would be happy if we just round to the nearest integer.
所以我想支持用户输入浮点数
So I want to support the user typing in floating point
都是小数点，但到最后,
values with decimal points, but at the end of the day,
例如，我只想将结果四舍五入到最接近的整数。
I just want to round the result to the nearest possible integer, for instance.
事实证明 Python 也内置了一些功能。
Well it turns out that here too Python comes with some functionality built in.
事实上，如果我们回到之前的 URL
And in fact, if we return to this URL from earlier
其中列出了所有 Python 内置函数,
wherein all of the Python built-in functions are listed,
有一种叫做“圆形”
there's one called "round" which does exactly
正如我们所期望的，它接受一个数字作为输入
as we would expect, it takes as input a number
然后四舍五入，例如，最接近的整数。
and then rounds it for us, for instance, to the nearest integer.
但如果我们仔细看看这些文件
But if we look a little closer at that documentation as we can here--
我会提供一个摘录
I'll provide an excerpt--
这是函数在文档中的样子。
this is what the function looks like in the documentation.
回想一下之前我们看过的打印文档
And recall that earlier we looked at the documentation for print
这是相似的精神，这表明我们不只是
and this is similar in spirit that this shows us not just
函数的名称，但它的可用参数，即,
the name of the function but its available parameters, that is,
我们在使用这个函数时可以提供的输入。
inputs that we can provide when using this function.
但这也有点神秘，就像“印刷”一样,
But this is a little cryptic too, just like Print was,
它添加了一些语法。
and it adds some syntax.
让我想想。
So let's see.
这个函数的名称当然是 Round
The name of this function here is of course Round
它的第一个参数是一个数字。
and its first argument is a number.
注意这次没有恒星，没有恒星物体
Notice this time there's no star, there's no star objects
就像印刷品一样。
like there was for print.
Round 函数的第一个参数是一个数，句号。
The Round function takes just one number as its first argument, period.
这是它的位置参数。
That's its positional parameter.
但请注意这个语法。
But notice this syntax.
这是编程或技术的惯例
And this is a convention in programming or technology
更一般地说，一般来说，当你看到方括号
more generally, generally speaking, when you see square brackets
这样的文件，这意味着你是
and documentation like this, this means that you're
即将看到一些可有可无的东西。
about to see something optional.
这意味着如果你想
And so what this means is that if you want
以更精确地指定要使用整数函数的位数
to specify more precisely the number of digits that you want the round function
为了四舍五入，您可以在这里通过添加逗号和那个数字来指定它。
to round to, you can specify it here by adding a comma and then that number.
所以如果我们读了文档如果你没有指定一些数字,
So if we read the documentation, if you don't specify a number of digits,
只要指定要舍入的数字，它就舍入到最接近的整数。
you just specify the number to round, it rounds to the nearest integer.
但是假设你想去十分之一的地方，或者百分之一的地方
But suppose you want around to the tenths place, or the hundredths place
就是小数点后面的一两个数字,
that is one or two digits after the decimal point,
为了更精确，你可以另外传入逗号1或者2。
you could additionally pass in comma 1 or comma 2 to be more precise.
文件上是这么说的。
So that's what the documentation, there is saying.
看看我们能不能把它转换成实际的代码。
Let's see if we can't then translate this to some actual code for us.
所以如果我现在回到 VS 代码，我考虑
So if I go back now to VS Code and I consider
我想继续，我可以用几种方法来做。
that I want to go ahead and round x and y, I can do this in a couple of ways.
我可以做圆周 x + y，但是你知道，我
I could do round x + y, but you know, I'd
实际上我更喜欢把它分成两行。
actually kind of prefer to break this now out into two lines.
我不需要，这里有理智的人可能不同意,
I don't have to, and reasonable people here might disagree,
但是我想回到我打印 z 的场景,
but I'd like to revert to a scenario where I'm printing z,
这样我就可以对自己，对别人更清楚一点,
so that I can just a little more clearly to myself, to others,
假设 z = x + y 的四舍五入结果。
say z = the rounded result of x + y.
这不一定是更好的方法,
It's not necessarily the better way to do it,
但我更喜欢一个一个说出我的想法,
but I'm a little more comfortable with breaking out my thoughts one at a time,
特别是如果我想开始注释这些代码块。
especially if I want to start commenting each of these chunks of code.
好吧，让我下到我的终端窗口
All right, let me go down to my terminal window
现在运行 Python of Calculator.py。
now and run Python of Calculator.py.
X 是什么？
What's x?
我们再做一次1.2。
Let's do 1.2 again.
那就3.4吧。
Then let's do 3.4.
之前是4.6，但现在是
And now it was previously 4.6, but now it's
被四舍五入到最接近的整数，当然是5。
been rounded up to the nearest integer, which of course is going to be 5.
好吧，如果我想再改变一下呢？
All right, what if I wanted to change this a little further?
如果我想支持一个大数字呢,
What if I wanted to support maybe really big numbers,
大数字，不考虑四舍五入，让我们这样做。
big numbers, irrespective of rounding, let's just do something like this.
让我继续运行 Python 的 Calculator.py
Let me go ahead and run Python of Calculator.py
再加上999 + 1。
again and let me just add 999 + 1.
注意，我不需要输入小数点,
And notice, I don't have to type decimal points,
即使我转换成 float 我的程序
even though I'm converting to float, my program
只允许我输入小数点，但我不需要强制执行。
will just allow me to type decimal points, but I don't need to oblige.
答案当然应该是，实际上是1000,
The answer of course here should be, and is in fact, 1,000,
不管我们是否回头。
whether or not we round.
这只是整数的算术运算。
So that's just arithmetic with integers here.
但在美国，我们往往用逗号来格式化长数
But in the US, we tend to format long numbers by putting commas
每三位数之后或之前。
after or before every triple of digits.
其他国家则用句号和逗号代替。
Other countries flip it and they use periods and commas instead.
这是系统设置。
That's a system setting.
你可以在你自己的 Mac 或 PC 上改变它
You can change that on your own Mac or PC
或者 Python 或者其他任何语言的设备，但是对我来说，我
or device for Python or any language, but for me, I'm
这里使用的是美国方法，即小数点的周期
using the US approach here, which is periods for decimal points
分隔符的逗号。
and commas for separators.
如果我想输出成1000呢？
What if I wanted this to be outputted as 1,000?
只是为了更清楚地表明这是1000而不是100。
Just to make it a little more clear that it's 1,000 and not something like 100.
如果是100万，那就更有用了
That's even more useful when it's like one million--
一百万。
1,000,000.
如果我们能自动
Wouldn't it be nice if we could automatically
也输出这些数字吗？
output those numbers as well?
事实证明我们可以。
Well, it turns out that we can.
有一种方法可以使用 Python 来实际指定我们
There is a way using Python to actually specify that we
希望包含像这样的逗号。
want to include commas like this.
现在我们有机会把我们的老朋友 F 弦带回来。
And here we have an opportunity to bring back our old friend, the F string.
首先，让我做一些不那么有成效的事情。
First, let me do something that's not that productive.
先让我来。
First let me do this.
让我打印出 z 的值，但是等一下。
Let me print out the value of z, but wait a minute.
我不能直接说“ z”因为字面意思就是打印 z
I can't just say "z" because that's literally going to print z
在屏幕上。
on the screen.
让我像以前一样用那些卷曲的支架把它包起来,
So let me wrap it with those curly braces like I did before,
但这还不够。
but that too was not enough.
我需要在字符串的开头加一个 F
I literally needed to add an F at the beginning of my string
告诉 Python 这是一个 F 字符串，一个格式化的字符串。
to tell Python that this is an F string, a format string.
现在要打印出来，不是很有趣，只是 z 的值
That now is going to print out, not very interestingly, just the value of z
本身。
itself.
所以我会不遗余力地打印 z 实际上我可以
So I'm going to great lengths just to print z when really I could have just
传递 z 作为唯一的参数。
passed z as the sole argument.
但为了确保我没有弄坏它，我们再来一次。
But just to ensure that I haven't broken it, let's do this again.
999 + 1，回车。
999 + 1, Enter.
好吧，还是1000。
OK, it's still 1,000.
所以我没有让事情变得更糟。
So I didn't make anything worse.
但是请注意——不幸的是，这个语法有点神秘——
But notice-- and this syntax is unfortunately a bit cryptic--
注意到我真的可以做到这一点。
notice that I can actually do this.
我可以在 z 后面加个冒号，之后加个逗号。
I can put a colon after the z and I can put a comma thereafter.
这看起来很神秘，不可否认，甚至我
This looks very cryptic, admittedly, and even I
必须不断地在文档中查找这样的内容
have to constantly look things like this up in the documentation
记住句法。
to remember the syntax.
但在这里，让我再运行一次。
But here, let me run it again.
Python 的 Calculator.py，9991，现在注意
Python of Calculator.py, 999 1 and now notice
这个号码已经自动为我格式化了。
that the number has been automatically formatted for me.
如果我在另一个国家或地区,
If I were in a different country or locale,
我完全可以覆盖这一点，使用句点而不是逗号或老虎钳
I could absolutely override this to use periods instead of commas or vise
反之亦然。
versa.
但在这种情况下，它只是自动发生在我身上。
But in this case here, it's just happening for me automatically.
因此，我们也看到了一个真正格式化字符串意味着什么的提示。
So there too we see a hint of what it means to really format a string.
还有更大的能量
There's even more power--
内置更强大的能力。
more powerful capabilities built into that.
好吧，我暂停一下看看有没有
All right, let me pause here to see if there's
关于浮点数、四舍五入或 F 字符串的使用的任何问题。
any questions now on floats, on rounding, or on this use of F strings.
观众: 是的，我有一个问题。
AUDIENCE: Yes, so I have a question.
所以当使用花车时，是否有一个帽子
So when using floats, is there like a cap
它能有多少个小数点？
to how many decimal points it can have?
大卫 · 马兰: 一个非常好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: A really good question.
所以，浮动，是的，这是一个问题，我们不久将重新讨论。
So floats, yes, and this is a problem we'll revisit before long.
Floats 不能无限精确地表示数字。
Floats cannot represent numbers infinitely precisely.
简而言之，因为计算机只有这么多内存。
In a nutshell, because computers only have so much memory.
他们只有有限的内存。
They only have a finite amount of memory.
你和我在电脑里的硬件数量是有限的,
You and I only have a finite amount of hardware inside of the computer,
所以在某个时候，他们必须要转过来。
so at some point, they're going to have to round.
现在我在自动巡视。
Right now I'm rounding automatically.
实际上，计算机最终将不得不为我们做到这一点,
Effectively computers will eventually have to do that for us,
但我们很快就会发现这是一个根本性的问题。
but we'll see that as a fundamental problem before long.
请允许我回过头来看浮动的最后几个例子
Allow me to turn back just for a few final examples on float
在我们介绍一些最后的例子之前
before we introduce a few final examples that allow us not just
使用函数，但使我们自己。
to use functions, but to make our own.
让我提议，我们也尝试在这里的一点分裂我们的手。
Let me propose that we also try our hands at a bit of division here.
让我提议我们现在修改这个计算器
Let me propose that we modify this calculator now
还有几辆花车，不过我们现在就开始吧
to still take a couple of floats, but let's now just do
简单一点的东西
something a little simpler than--
和这个有点不同，只是做 x 除以 y。
a little different from this, just doing x divided by y.
让我继续，去掉我的格式字符串
And let me go ahead and get rid of my format string
暂时保持简单，打印出 z。
and just keep it simple for now, printing out z instead.
我们在这里会看到什么？
And what are we going to see here?
只是一些简单的划分。
Well just some simple division.
那么 Python 的 Calculator.py，让我们做一个类似2除以3的运算,
So Python of Calculator.py, let's do something like 2 divided by 3,
当然我得到0.66666。
and of course I get 0.66666.
对于刚才伊森的问题，它似乎是有限的。
And to Ethan's question a moment ago, it does seem to be finite.
这里的舍入方式并不奇怪，但我似乎只看到这么多数字。
It's not rounding in a weird way here, but I only seem to see so many digits.
这就是以这种方式使用浮点数的必然性。
That's an inevitability of using a float in this way.
相比之下，正如您所知，现在 Python 中的整数
By contrast, just so you know, integers nowadays in Python
你想要多大就有多大。
can be as big as you want them to be.
与其他语言不同，它没有上限
Unlike other languages, there is no upper bound
现在在 Python 中 INT 可以有多大，但是
on how big an INT can be now in Python, but there
是浮点值的精确度的界限。
is a bound on just how precise a floating point value can be.
好了，现在我有了一个简单的部门,
All right, now that I've got some simple division working here,
我们绕过去吧。
let's go ahead and round this.
把这个非常长的数字0.6666666舍去会很好，以此类推
It would be nice to round this really long number 0.6666666 and so forth
也许只有小数点后两位。
to maybe just two decimal places.
不过，我们已经看到了如何使用 round 来实现这一点，至少在其文档中已经看到了。
We've seen how to do this with round, though, at least in its documentation.
我们不要把这个问题归结为最接近的智力问题,
Let's just round this not to the nearest INT,
通过传入 x 除以 y 这是一个参数，一旦数学
by passing in just x divided by y, which is one argument, once the math is
在括号内完成，我不想只传递一个参数。
done inside of the parentheses, I don't want to pass in just one argument.
我想传入2这样我就可以指定 n 个数字,
I want to pass in two so that I can specify n digits,
数字的个数，这是 round 的第二个参数。
number of digits, which you'll recall was the second parameter for round.
让我继续运行 Python 的 Calculator.py。
Let me go ahead and run Python of Calculator.py.
我也会这么做
I'll do the same thing--
2然后是30.67。
2 and then 3, 0.67.
这里我们也看到了一种舍入的方法不仅仅是舍入最近的整数,
So here too we see a way of rounding now, not just to a nearest integer,
而是一个最接近的数字。
but to a nearest number of digits.
但还有另一种方法。
But there's another way to do this here.
事实上，这又让我们想起了 F 字符串的例子。
And in fact, this evokes our F string example again.
让我先把这个换了。
Let me go ahead and change this.
假设您不记得 round 函数，或者由于某种原因,
Suppose that you didn't remember the round function or, for some reason,
你不想用它。
you didn't want to use it.
相反，您只需要使用一个格式化字符串。
You instead want to just use a format string.
好吧，我们去那里。
Well, let's go there.
让我做“ z”但是让我用那些卷曲的支架把它包起来。
Let me do "z" but let me surround it with those curly braces.
让我在开头加上 F，再说一遍，这还不是很有趣。
Let me add the F at the beginning, and again, this is not interesting yet.
这只是打印出 z，但我增加了更多的复杂性
This is just going to print out z, but I'm adding a lot more complexity
把它变成 F 字符串。
to turn it into an F string.
但是请注意，我可以在变量名后面，冒号后面做其他事情。
But notice I can do something else after my variable name, after the colon.
如果这是一个大整数,
If this were going to be a big integer, I
可能需要像前面那样用逗号来分隔每个三重数
might want to use a comma like before to separate each triple of numbers
用逗号。
with commas.
但我没有。
But I don't.
我将使用不同的字符序列。
I'm going to use a different sequence of characters.
我会说0.2 F，这也是我得到的非常神秘的东西之一
I'm going to say 0.2F and this too is one of these very cryptic things I have
经常抬头看，因为我忘了如果我不经常使用它。
to constantly look up because I forget if I don't use it that often.
所以如果这看起来特别奇怪，不要害怕，但这是,
So don't be intimidated if this looks especially weird, but this is,
根据文件记录
according to the documentation, the way you
使用 F 字符串指定要打印的数字数量。
specify using an F string how many digits you want to print.
让我运行这个版本的计算器。
So let me run this version of the calculator.
输入2和3得到的结果一模一样。
Type in 2 and then 3, we get the exact same thing.
但是，这和我的说法是一致的
But again, this is just consistent with my claim
在编程中，我们经常可以解决同样的问题
that in programming we can so very often solve the same problem
在很多方面。
in multiple ways.
这就是 F 字符串方法来解决同样的问题。
This is just now the F string approach to that very same problem.
好吧，哪个更好？
All right, which one is better?
看情况。
It depends.
在这种情况下，它们是非常相似的。
In this case, they're pretty equivalent.
不过，您可以想象，有时候使用一个函数是有用的
You can imagine, though, it being useful to use a function sometimes
这样你就可以传入一个像 n 位数这样的参数作为第二个参数,
so that you can pass in an argument like n digits as that second argument,
或者你可以想象提前决定你想要0.2
or you can imagine just deciding in advance that you want 0.2
然后像这样写。
and then writing it like this.
现在让我们从关注字符串和整数过渡到
Let's transition now from focusing on strings and on integers and on
现在将重点放在函数本身上。
floats to focusing now on functions themselves.
我们从今天开始关注如何
We began today by focusing on how you can
使用 Python 附带的函数。
use functions that come with Python.
但如果你能发明自己的函数,
But wouldn't it be nice if you could invent your own functions,
特别是如果，就我们之前的观点，你发现
especially if, to our point earlier, you find
一次又一次地解决同样的问题？
yourself solving the same kind of problem again and again?
Python 附带了 print 函数，这很好
It's nice that Python comes with the print function
因为能够在屏幕上打印东西真的很有用,
because it's really useful to be able to print things on the screen,
但是如果你能在屏幕上打印出特定的东西，那该多好啊
but wouldn't it be nice if you could print specific things on the screen
调用你自己的函数？
by just calling your own function?
我提议我们这么做。
Well let me propose that we do this.
让我回到 VS 代码这里，让我提议我们回到 Hello.py。
Let me go back to VS Code here and let me propose that we go back to Hello.py.
我要重新打开我们之前放在那里的 Hello. py
I'm going to reopen Hello.py where we left it before
我现在要向你求婚了
and I'm going to go ahead now and propose
我们考虑如何开始进一步改善这个问题
that we consider how we can start improving this further by making
我们自己的功能。
our own function.
我今天写了很多程序，只是说你好
I have written so many programs today that just say Hello
每次我使用打印。
and each time I'm using print.
但如果从今天开始,
But wouldn't it have been nice if, from the beginning of today,
我们可以只调用一个名为 Hello 的函数，它只为我们表示 Hello？
we could just call a function called Hello that just says Hello for us?
而几年前 Python 的作者却没有
Now the authors of Python years ago didn't
认为我们需要一个特殊的函数来说 Hello,
think that we need a special function just to say Hello,
但我希望那样的生活存在。
but I would like that to exist.
我说了这么多次你好，我只是想
I'm saying Hello so many times, I just want
能够调用函数 Hello。
to be able to call a function Hello.
所以我要从头开始。
So I'm going to start from scratch here.
我要删除之前的所有代码
I'm going to delete all of my code from earlier
假设有一个名为 Hello 的函数存在。
and I'm going to pretend for the moment that a function called Hello exists.
我要像以前一样。
And I'm going to do just as I did before.
我将通过输入函数得到用户名,
I'm going to get the user's name with the input function,
问你叫什么，问号。
asking what's your name, question mark.
现在我要调用一个函数 Hello
And now I'm going to call a function Hello
然后打印出用户名。
and then I'm going to print out the user's name.
现在我承认，你好不存在，所以坏事就要发生了,
Now I will admit, Hello doesn't exist, so bad things are about to happen,
但是让我们看看。
but let's see what.
让我下到我的终端窗口。
Let me go down to my terminal window.
让我运行 Python of Hello.py。
Let me run Python of Hello.py.
我觉得第一句台词应该没问题，因为之前这招很管用。
I think the first line is going to be OK because that worked before.
事实上，它提醒了我的名字。
And indeed, it's prompting me for my name.
让我输入大卫。
So let me type in David.
第二行代码显然在调用
The second line of code is apparently calling
一个看起来像 Hello 的函数，因为它为什么是一个函数？
a function that looks like it's called Hello, because why is it a function?
它有一个括号和紧随其后的一个闭括号。
It has a parenthesis and a closed parenthesis immediately after it.
我们使用的每个函数都是这样的。
And that's what every function we've used has looked like.
但 Python 不会认出这个的。
But Python is not going to recognize this one.
当我现在按下 Enter 键时，我得到一个名称错误。
When I hit Enter now, I get a name error.
名字“你好”没有定义，你的意思是帮助吗？
Name "Hello" is not defined, did you mean Help?
我没有，虽然我现在需要的是一些帮助,
I didn't, although it's opportune that's what I need at this point is some help,
但是我遇到这个错误是因为什么呢？
but I am encountering this error because why?
这个函数根本不存在。
The function just doesn't exist.
那么如何使这个函数存在呢？
So how do I make this function exist?
我需要创建它自己使用这个关键字，DEF，DEF 的定义。
Well I need to create it myself using this key word, DEF, DEF for define.
正如 STR 是字符串的简称 INT 是整数的简称一样,
So here too, just as STR is short for string and INT is short for integer,
dEF 是定义的简称。
DEF is short for define.
如果你想定义，创建，发明你自己的函数,
If and when you want to define, create, invent your own functions,
您现在可以使用 Python 中的这个关键字来完成此操作。
you can do so using now this keyword in Python.
那么让我们回到我的代码这里，让我提议我们定义这个
So let me go back to my code here and let me propose that we define this
也许是这样。
perhaps in this way.
在我的档案的最上面，我将首先
At the very top of my file, I'm going to first take
定义一个名为 Hello 的函数的时间
a moment to define a function called Hello
使用 DEF Hello，开括号，闭括号，冒号。
using DEF Hello, open parenthesis, close parenthesis, colon.
这意味着 Python 将处理每一行代码
What this means now is that Python is going to treat every line of code
我在这个下面缩进，作为这个新函数 Hello 的意思。
that I indent underneath this one as the meaning of this new function, Hello.
因此 DEF 和空间一样重要。
So DEF is important as is the space.
我可以选择函数的名称我选择称它为 Hello。
I get to choose the name of the function and I'm choosing to call it Hello.
没有内容的括号表示这个函数现在
The parentheses with nothing inside means that this function at the moment
不需要任何输入，也没有争论。
is not going to take any inputs, no arguments there too.
冒号的意思是，请继续关注缩进。
The colon means, stay tuned for some indentation.
这行代码下面缩进的所有东西
Everything that's indented beneath this line of code
是这个函数的一部分。
is going to be part of this function.
这将是一个非常简短的函数——一行代码——
It's going to be a super short function-- one line of code--
它只会打印出“你好”
it's just going to print out "Hello."
但是现在在第1行和第2行，我已经发明了自己的函数 Hello。
But now on lines 1 and 2, I have invented my own function Hello.
注意这些神奇地出现在这里的点。
Notice these dots that have now magically appeared here.
这只是我的文本编辑器的一个设置,
This is just a setting of my text editor,
在这种情况下 VS 代码，这只是让我超级明确，我已经
VS Code in this case, that's just making super explicit to me that I've
按空格键四次，或者按 Tab 键一次,
hit the space bar four times, or equivalently the Tab key once,
它会自动转换成四个空格。
which is converted automatically to four spaces.
一般来说，我需要确保所有缩进的代码
Generally speaking, I'm going to need to make sure that all of my indented code
这样 Python 就知道它们都是同一个东西的一部分。
lines up now so that Python knows that it's all part of the same thing.
但在这种情况下很容易，因为它只是一条线。
But it's easy in this case because it's just a single line.
但是现在，由于行1和行2，函数 Hello
But now, thanks to lines 1 and 2, the function Hello
当我准备好在第6行使用它时，它将绝对存在。
will absolutely exist when I'm ready to use it on line 6.
那么让我下到我的终端窗口，运行 Python of Hello.py，Enter。
So let me go down to my terminal window and run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
我的名字又来了。
Here comes my name again.
现在当我按回车键时，我看到你好，大卫。
And now when I hit Enter, I now see Hello, David.
好吧，我们有点倒退了，对吧？
All right, we've kind of regressed though, right?
这里已经不像以前那么漂亮了。
This is not nearly as pretty as it once was.
我认为我们可以通过进一步改进来做得更好。
I think we can probably do better than this by improving things further.
为什么我们不考虑一下，我们该怎么做呢
Why don't we consider, though, how we might
把这个函数参数化？
say parameterize this same function?
也就是说，我们是否可以定制 Hello，将用户名作为输入
That is to say, can we customize Hello to maybe take the user's name as input
这样我们就可以说，不仅 Hello，而且人的名字都在一行，所有
so that we can say, not only Hello, but the person's name all on one line, all
一口气？
in one breath?
我觉得我们能做到。
Well I think we can do this.
让我提议我们这样做。
Let me propose that we do this as follows.
让我继续往上写代码让我进入这些括号,
Let me go ahead and up in my code, let me inside of these parentheses,
让我想出我自己的参数名。
let me come up with my own parameter name.
我有完全的选择，我要走了
I have complete choice here and I'm going
表示参数的名称将为“ To”。
to say that the name of my parameter will be the word To.
为什么？
Why?
因为我希望我的函数听起来像它代表的动词
Because I want my function to sound like the verb it represents--
你好。
Hello.
但你想跟谁打招呼呢？
But who do you want to say Hello to?
我要调用这个函数的参数
Well I'm going to call my parameter for this function
对，只是因为在英语里，听起来不错。
To, just because in English, it kind of sounds nice to me.
你好，你想和谁打招呼？
Hello To, who do you want to say Hello to?
所以我把这个参数调用为 To
That's why I'm calling this parameter To instead of something
像 x，y，z 一样简单。
simpler like x or y or z.
好吧，那我该怎么处理“到”这个词呢？
All right, well what do I want to do with the word To?
我可以做一些不同的事情。
Well I can do a couple of different things.
我们已经看到了很多实现 Hello 的不同方法。
We've seen like so many different ways to implement Hello.
为了方便语法，我在这里加个逗号。
Let me just add a comma there for grammar's sake.
然后让我把“ To”放在后面作为第二个论点
And then let me put the word To after that as the second argument
你好。
to the function Hello.
还有其他办法，我们见过很多办法,
There's other ways we can do this and we've seen so many,
但我觉得这个看起来有点清楚。
but this one looks a little clear to me, I'll say.
接下来会发生什么？
What's going to happen next?
我觉得我不需要这条额外的打印线。
Well I don't think I need this extra print line here.
我想我要做的是，我要在这里继续
I think what I'm going to do is this, I'm going to go ahead here
而不是手动打印出这个人的名字，我会说,
and print out not the person's name manually, I'm going to instead say,
你好，括号中的名字。
Hello parentheses name.
那我现在在做什么？
So what am I now doing?
在第1行和第2行，我定义了我自己的函数 Hello,
On lines 1 and 2 I'm defining my very own function called Hello,
但是这次，这个功能已经被设计出来了
but this time that function has been designed
以一个参数，一个单独的参数作为输入。
to take a parameter, a single parameter, as input.
我使用这个参数的值
And I'm using the value of that parameter which
我打电话到插入打印，使我不仅看到
I called To to plug into print so that I see not only
你好，还有那个人的名字。
Hello but also that person's name.
我在5号线上做什么？
What am I doing on line 5?
和往常一样，我只是得到用户名。
Same as always, I'm just getting the user's name.
6号线，我不只是打电话给你，我是路过的
Line 6, I'm not only calling Hello, I'm passing
作为参数输入 name 变量
as input the name variable as an argument
所以这就是传递给 Hello 的东西。
so that that's what gets passed into Hello.
这里发生的事情本质上是这样的
And what's happening here is essentially this--
即使这个变量在这里被称为 Name，当函数
even though the variable is called Name here, when the function
则计算机假定相同的值现在被调用。
itself is called, the computer assumes that same value is now called To.
因此 Name 实际上被复制到另一个名为
So Name is essentially copied to another variable called
这样，在 Hello 的上下文中，我可以对该变量说 Hello。
To so that in the context of Hello, I can say Hello to that variable instead.
我们马上就会知道，如果我们不把这些都弄清楚会发生什么。
And we'll see in a moment what happens if we don't keep those straight.
让我继续运行 Python of Hello.py，Enter。
Let me go ahead and run Python of Hello.py, Enter.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
现在我祈祷吧。
And now I'm crossing my fingers.
进来。
Enter.
好了。
There we go.
我们重新开始了，但是现在我有了自己的定制函数 Hello
We're back in business, but now I have my own custom function called Hello
这样我就可以跟特定的人打招呼了。
that's allowing me to say Hello to a specific person.
现在事情可以变得很有趣了。
And here's where now things can get really fancy.
如果希望 Hello 函数对某个特定的人说 Hello,
What if you wanted your Hello function to say Hello to someone specific,
但是，你知道吗如果你不知道你想跟谁打招呼,
but, you know what, if you don't know who you want to say Hello to,
你想向全世界问好,
you want to say Hello to the whole world,
可以为参数提供默认值。
you can give parameters default values.
我们已经看到了。
We've seen that.
回想一下，对于 print，SEP 有一个默认值,
Recall that with print there was a default value for SEP,
分离器。
for the separator.
END 有一个默认值，行结束。
There was a default value for END, the line ending.
我们也可以这样做，这里是语法。
We can do that too, and here's the syntax.
如果希望默认情况下获取此参数的值,
If you want the value of this parameter by default,
如果不是程序员提供的，等于“世界”
if not provided by the programmer, to be equal to "world,"
你可以在定义函数的同一行中这样做。
you literally do that in the same line you're defining the function.
我承认，这看起来越来越神秘了,
And I'll admit, it's starting to look more cryptic,
但我仍然只是定义了一个名为 Hello，it 的函数
but I'm still just defining a function called Hello, it
接受一个名为 To 的参数，但我正在赋值它
takes a parameter called To, but I'm assigning it
等号为“ world”的默认值，以防程序员
with the equal sign a default value of "world," just in case the programmer
不会用争吵来打电话给 Hello。
doesn't call Hello with an argument.
我们可以在这里看到。
And we can see this here.
让我用两种方式更改代码以使用 Hello。
Let me change my code to use Hello in two ways.
在第5行，我将非常简单地调用 Hello，没有参数。
On line 5, I'm going to very simply call Hello, no arguments.
然后在第六行，我会得到名字。
Then on line 6, I'm going to get the name.
第7行，我将用一个参数调用 Hello。
Line 7, I'm going to call Hello with an argument.
所以您将看到 Hello 现在有两种用法。
So you'll see Hello now being used in two ways.
让我继续运行 Python of Hello.py。
Let me go ahead and run Python of Hello.py.
我输入我的名字。
I'll type in my name.
有意思。
Oh, interesting.
注意，我已经看到了 Hello，world，但那是
Notice I already see Hello, world, but that's
因为第5行发生在第6行之前，但是一旦我键入我的名字,
expected because line 5 happens before line 6, but once I type my name,
现在节目要更有礼貌一点，跟我打个招呼
now the program is going to be a little more polite and say hello to me
私下里。
personally.
因此，我们看到了相对简单但新的语法
So there too, we see with relatively simple but new syntax
你如何实现功能非常相似的精神打印
how you can implement functionality very similar in spirit to what the print
函数自动给我们。
function gave us automatically.
现在你可以自己控制了。
Now you have control over doing that yourself.
但现在让我也说明这一点。
But let me now make this point too.
定义自己的函数的要点之一
One of the whole points of defining your own functions
是一个，只是为了避免重复自己一遍又一遍。
is one, just to avoid having to repeat yourself again and again.
你不必真的保持重造轮子
You don't have to actually keep reinventing the wheel
继续使用打印函数，一次又一次,
and keep using the print function again, and again, and again,
如果你只是想打个招呼。
if you just want to say Hello.
如果我现在能移动这个代码
Wouldn't it be nice now if I could move this code
我为定义 Hello 函数而写的程序为了更戏剧化一点,
that I wrote for defining the Hello function, and just to be dramatic,
我会按回车键很多次，往下50行,
I'm going to hit Enter a whole lot of times, 50 lines down,
并把我的 Hello 的定义放在这个文件的后面。
and put my definition of Hello way further down in this file.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，只是为了眼不见心不烦,
Well, just for in the spirit of out of sight, out of mind,
因为如果我现在回到我的节目开始
because if I now rewind to the start of my program, now
你可以理所当然地认为 Hello 是一个函数。
you can take for granted that, oh, Hello is a function.
为什么？
Why?
因为它在第一行有一个开括号和一个闭括号
Because it's there on line 1 and it has an open parenthesis and a closed
括号，到目前为止它的意思是，调用这个函数。
parenthesis, which, up until now has meant, call this function.
然后在第2行，我们从用户那里得到一个变量
And then on line 2 we're getting a variable from the user
输入他们的名字然后我们调用 Hello 传递那个值。
by typing in their name and then we're calling Hello, passing in that value.
在这一点上，我可以理所当然地认为 Hello 是存在的,
Well at this point, I can just take for granted that Hello exists,
即使它在文件中的位置更低，或者，我们将在未来几周看到,
even if it's way down further in the file or, as we'll see in future weeks,
即使是在完全不同的文件里。
even if it's in a different file altogether.
但这里有个问题。
But there's a problem here.
让我继续运行这个版本的 Hello.py。
And let me go ahead and run this version of Hello.py.
注意，只要我运行解释器 Hello.py 的 Python,
Notice that as soon as I run the interpreter, Python of Hello.py,
我看到一个名称错误，名称 Hello 没有定义。
I see a name error, name Hello is not defined.
再问一次，你是说帮忙吗？
Again, did you mean Help?
再说一遍，很合身。
Well, again, fitting.
我确实需要一些帮助，但我并不想调用这个函数 Help。
I do need some help here, but I didn't mean to call the function Help.
但问题是，巨蟒只是字面上的意思。
The problem here, though, is that Python is just taking me literally.
我已经在这里定义了我的函数 Hello,
I have defined my function Hello all the way down here,
但我正在努力使用它的方式在这里。
but I'm trying to use it way up here.
这是不允许的。
And that's not allowed.
Python 的解释器将逐字逐句地向您介绍
Python's interpreter is going to take you literally
如果你使用一个函数，它必须已经
and if you use a function, it must already
在你调用它的时候已经存在。
exist by the time you are calling it.
那我该怎么补救？
So how do I fix this?
显然我做不到。
Well, apparently I can't do that.
我必须在文件的最顶部定义任何我想要的函数,
I have to define any functions I want at the very top of my file,
但这也会给我带来一点麻烦
but that too could get me into a bit of trouble
最终，因为如果我不断地在我想要的地方定义一个函数
eventually because if I constantly have to define a function above where I want
要使用它，你需要反向编写代码,
to use it, you're kind of writing code in reverse,
你不断地在这上面写函数，在这上面,
you're constantly writing functions up here, up here,
从上到下，而不是按逻辑编写代码。
up here, as opposed to writing your code logically, top to bottom.
让我用更标准的方法来解决这个问题，就是这样做。
So let me fix this in a more standard way, which is to do this.
一般来说，您确实希望将代码的主要部分
Generally speaking, you do want to put the main part of your code
在你档案的最上面。
at the top of your file.
实际上，我还要定义函数 Main。
And in fact, I'm going to go so far as to define my function, called Main.
这不是必需的，但是在数据约定中,
It's not a requirement, but it's in data convention,
这对读者来说意味着
and this just connotes to the reader that this
是我计划的主要部分。
is the main part of my program.
我现在要去掉我的空 Hello 调用，只传递一个版本
I'm going to get rid of my empty Hello call now and only pass in one version
你好，名字。
with Hello, name.
然后这里，再往下几行,
And then down here, a couple of lines further down,
实际上我将定义 Hello 函数。
I'll actually define my Hello function.
不幸的是，现在我已经用这种方式重新排序了函数,
Unfortunately, now that I've reordered the functions in this way,
将代码的主要部分放在顶部，Hello 放在底部
by putting the main part of my code at the top and Hello at the bottom
所以如果我继续跑的话，我的逻辑会自上而下地流动
so that my logic kind of flows top to bottom, if I go ahead and run
Python of Hello.py，Enter.
Python of Hello.py, Enter.
什么都没发生。
Nothing whatsoever happens.
如果我再这么做，什么都不会发生。
If I do it again, nothing whatsoever happens.
这到底是为什么？
Well, why in the world is this?
因为我定义了一个名为
Well, just because I've defined a function called
Main 和我已经定义了一个名为 Hello 的函数,
Main and I've defined a function called Hello,
并不意味着我真的打过电话
doesn't mean that I've actually called--
两者都是。
that is used-- either of them.
是的，我在 Main 中使用 Hello，但是没有人
Yes, I'm using Hello inside of Main, but no one
告诉 Python 实际使用或调用 Main。
is telling Python to actually use or call Main.
所以为了整理这个文件我最后要做的就是,
So in order to tidy this up, the last thing I need to do in this file,
看起来，实际上是调用我的主函数。
it seems, is actually call my main function.
实际上，通过这样调用 main 函数,
And, in fact, by calling my main function in this way,
它让我摆脱了麻烦，因为现在我首先定义了 Main
it gets me out of trouble because now I'm defining Main first
但我还没打电话给你。
but I'm not calling Hello yet.
接下来我要定义 Hello 但我不会再打 Hello 了。
I'm defining Hello next, but I'm not calling Hello next.
我只在这个文件的最后调用 Main
I only at the very end of this file call Main
它的作用就是在这里运行这个代码,
which has the effect of running this code up here,
which has the effect of running this code down here,
因此我可以整理我的文件
and it allows me therefore to organize my file
按照我想要的方式来安排我的职能包括最上面的 Main,
and order my functions in any way I want, including Main at the very top,
并最终解决了 Python 不知道发生了什么的问题。
and solving ultimately that problem of Python not knowing what's going on.
现在需要注意的是，我定义了我的函数
Now it's important to note that I defined my function
你好，作为一个论点，然后我
Hello as taking an argument To and then I
将变量的值传递给该函数
passed into that function the value of the variable
我想对它说 Hello，这是一个名为 Name 的变量。
that I wanted to say Hello to, that is the variable called Name.
因为假设我做了一些不同的事情。
Because suppose I had done something a little bit differently.
假设我没有定义 Hello 参数,
Suppose that I hadn't defined Hello is taking an argument,
所以我只是删除了 To 和它的默认值“ world”
so I just remove mention of To and its default value "world."
回到我的主函数
And I go back up to my main function and I just
调用 Hello 本身而不传入任何参数。
call Hello itself without passing in any arguments.
现在让我再做一次改变,
And now let me go ahead and make my one more change,
严格来说，再犯一个错误，我就不客气了
one more mistake technically, let me go ahead
然后尝试天真地在 Hello 函数中打印 Name 的值。
and just try to naively print out the value of Name in the Hello function.
所以现在我要说清楚，在第2行的主函数中,
So now to be clear, in my main function on line 2,
我定义了一个名为 Name 的变量，并将返回值赋给它
I'm defining my variable called Name and assigning it the return value
从用户输入函数。
of the input function from the user.
那我就打电话给你。
I'm then just calling Hello.
在 Hello 函数中，它现在不再接受任何参数,
In my Hello function, which now no longer takes any arguments,
我正在调用 print，传入 Hello 逗号,
I am calling print, passing in Hello comma,
然后立即传入 Name，即变量
and then immediately passing in Name, the variable
我得到了用户的输入。
into which I got the user's input.
但问题是这个名字现在只存在于 Main 中。
But the catch is that name exists now only in Main.
看看我运行这个版本的程序时会发生什么
And so watch what happens when I try to run this version of the program
使用 Python Hello.py。
with Python Hello.py.
我按了回车键。
I hit Enter.
系统提示输入我的名字，D-A-V-I-D，回车。
I'm prompted for my name, D-A-V-I-D, Enter.
然后，啊！
And, argh!
名称错误。
A name error.
未定义名称“ Name”。
Name "Name" is not defined.
所以这实际上是一个范围的问题。
So it turns out that this is actually an issue of what's called scope.
范围指的是仅存在于您定义它的上下文中的变量。
Scope refers to a variable only existing in the context in which you defined it.
在我定义这个变量的时候，在我的 main 函数中,
So insofar as I define this variable, Name in my main function,
我只能在 name 函数中使用这个变量。
I can only use that variable in my name function.
我不能使用它，因为我尝试在 Hello 函数中使用它。
I can't use it as I've tried to here in my Hello function.
它不存在于那个所谓的范围内。
It doesn't exist in that so-called scope.
所以这就是为什么现在，如果我倒带并撤销所有这些改变,
And so this is why now, if I rewind and undo all of those changes,
你会看到我故意从主函数中传递 Main
you'll see that I'm deliberately passing Main from my main function
进入我的 Hello 函数。
into my Hello function.
现在在 Hello 函数中，它在技术上有一个不同的名称。
And now in the Hello function, it technically has a different name.
在那种情况下叫做 To，不过没关系。
It's called To in that context, but that's fine.
每个函数完全可以命名自己的变量
It's completely up to each individual function to name its own variables
或者命名它自己的论点，但这是现在的一种方式
or name its own arguments, but this is a way now
我把变量的值传递给 Hello 函数
that I'm handing to the Hello function the value of that variable
所以它也可以被 Hello 打印出来。
so it can be printed by Hello as well.
我们还可以在这里添加最后一个花絮。
And there's one final flourish we can add here.
现在我们已经实现了 Hello，您将注意到只有 Hello
Now that we've implemented Hello, you'll notice that Hello only
有所谓的副作用。
has a so-called side effect.
它只会把一些东西打印到屏幕上。
It only prints out something to the screen.
如果我希望我的函数本身没有副作用呢,
Well, what if I also want my function to not have a side effect, per se,
但实际上还给我一个值？
but actually hand me back a value?
回想一下，input 函数返回一个值,
Recall that the input function returns a value,
用户键入的字符串。
the string that the user typed in.
回想一下，INT 函数返回一个值。
Recall that the INT function returns a value.
Float 函数返回传递给它的值。
The float function returns a value that was passed into it.
你可以在这里用最后一个关键词，字面上的意思
Well you can use one final keyword here, literally
返回自己显式返回一个值。
Return to return a value explicitly yourself.
事实上，让我们回到 VS 代码这里，我
In fact, let me go back to VS Code here, and I
我想我们应该把注意力转移到 Calculator.py 上
think we'll return our attention to Calculator.py
看看我们能不能实现另一个版本的 Calculator.py
and see if we can't implement one other version of Calculator.py that actually
有我们自己的函数，甚至返回一个值。
has our own function that even returns a value.
现在我要打开计算器/py
So I'm going to go ahead and open up calculator/py
我想这次我会像以前一样把所有东西都扔掉,
and I think this time I'm going to throw everything away as before,
我要开始实践我们在这里所宣扬的。
and I'm just going to start practicing what we're preaching here.
定义一个名为 Main 的函数
Define a function called Main which is now going
成为我职责的主要部分。
to be the main part of my function.
现在声明一个变量 x,
Let's go ahead and now declare a variable called x,
并在询问用户后将其分配给用户输入的转换版本,
and assign it to the converted version of the user's input after asking them,
x 是什么？
what's x?
再一次，一行代码，就像我们之前做过的。
So again, a line of code quite like we've done before.
假设现在我要做的就是平方这个值。
And suppose now that what I want to do is square this value.
我想取用户输入的数字
I want to take the number that the user has typed in
把它提高到2的幂。
and raise it to the power of 2.
所以2的平方等于4。
So 2 squared would be 4.
3的平方等于9。
3 squared would be 9.
4的平方等于16等等。
4 squared would be 16, and so forth.
那么我该如何实现一个函数呢
Well how do I go about implementing a function literally
叫做 Square 实际上并没有内置 Python？
called Square which actually doesn't come with Python built-in?
让我暂时假设它确实存在
Well, let me assume for the moment that it does exist, and let
我说这样的话
me say something like this--
让我继续说，印刷，如何
let me go ahead and say that printing, how
关于 x 的平方是 x 的逗号平方。
about x squared is comma square of x.
我做了什么？
So what have I done?
我定义了一个名为 Main 的函数，并实现了两行代码。
I've defined a function called Main and I've implemented two lines.
第一行提示用户输入一个值
The first of these lines prompts the user for a value
并将其转换为 INT 并将其存储在一个名为 x 的变量中。
x and converts it to an INT and stores it in a variable called x.
在第3行，我说 x 的平方是，然后
On line 3, I then say x squared is and then
我将第二个参数传递给 print 函数，不管返回值是什么
I pass a second argument to the print function, whatever the return
值是一个平方函数。
value is of a square function.
但平方并不存在，我给你们看这个,
But squared doesn't exist and I'll show you this here,
如果我现在在底部调用 Main 并运行 Python 的 Calculator.py,
if I now call Main at the bottom and I run Python of Calculator.py,
我会看到 x 是2然后我会看到一大堆错误一个名字错误,
I'll see that x is 2 and then I see a whole bunch of errors, a name error,
名称 Square 未定义。
name Square is not defined.
这不是打错了，只是函数不存在。
So this isn't a typo here, it's just the function doesn't exist.
但我想我可以让它存在于这里。
But I think I can make it exist here.
让我继续定义另一个名为 Square 的函数。
Let me go ahead and define another function called Square.
接下来我要说的是一个数字
This one's going to take in a number and I'm
就像很多程序员一样，通常称它为 n,
going to call it generically n, as many a programmer would,
只是为了表示任何旧的数字。
just to represent any old number.
然后我要做什么，才能得到 n 的平方呢？
And then what do I want to do in order to square n?
一个数字的平方其实就是它自己乘以它自己,
Well a number squared is really just itself times itself,
所以我要这么做
so I'm going to do this--
N 乘以 n。
n times n.
但仅仅自己算 n 乘以 n 是不够的。
But it's not enough just to do the math yourself, n times n.
必须返回实际值 n 乘以 n
You're going to have to return the actual value n times n
这就是我们的新关键词。
and that's our new keyword here.
当我这么做的时候，看看会发生什么。
When I now do this, watch what happens.
Python 的 Calculator.py，Enter。
Python of Calculator.py, Enter.
X 说应该是2，x 的平方是4。
X say shall be 2, x squared is 4.
现在让我继续，说 x 现在是3。
Let me go ahead now and say x is now 3.
X 的平方现在是9。
X squared is now 9.
所以我实现了我自己的函数，它返回一个值的平方
So I've implemented my very own function that returns the square of a value
因为我用的是 return 关键字
and because I'm using the return keyword, that
确保我可以传递这个的返回值
ensures that I can pass the return value of this, just
比如输入或 INT 或 float 的返回值,
like the return value of input or INT or float, to another function,
比如印刷品。
like print instead.
这里也有很多方法可以解决同样的问题。
And here too there's going to be so many ways to solve this same problem.
实际上我可以把 n 提高到2的幂。
I can actually raise n to the power of 2.
我们以前没有见过这种语法，但是如果您
We've not seen this syntax before, but if you
像这样用两个星号，两颗星，把左边的东西举起来
use two asterisks like this, two stars, that raises the thing on the left
右边的电源。
to the power on the right.
或者在 Python 中有一个名为
Or it turns out there is in Python a function called
因为提升了某种东西的力量
POW for raising something to the power that
接受两个参数，第一个是数字，第二个是
takes two arguments, the first of which is the number, the second of which
是指数。
is the exponent.
因此，实际上有很多方法可以解决同样的问题
So there too, there's just so many ways to actually solve that same problem
我也是。
as well.
那么最终，我们在这里做了什么？
So ultimately, what have we done here?
我们首先介绍了函数——这些动作或动词，其中许多
We first introduced functions-- these actions or verbs, many of which
内置到 Python 中，可以在自己的代码中使用。
come built into Python that you can just use in your own code.
然后我们引入变量，通过它们可以存储这些返回值
We then introduced variables via which you could store those return values
然后再做点别的。
and then maybe do something more with it.
到头来也一样。
At the end of the day too.
你现在有能力去创造，去发明你自己的功能
You now have the ability to create, to invent your own functions
来解决像 Hello 这样的简单问题，或者在几周内
to solve simple problems like Hello, or in the weeks
更复杂，更有挑战性，更有趣的问题。
to come-- much more sophisticated, more challenging, more fun problems as well.